A federal jury begins deliberations today
over the sentence for the 2018  Pittsburgh synagogue shooter.
And at least 11 people have died in  flooding in Beijing's western suburbs.
Good morning. I'm Korva Coleman, from NPR  News, and here are today's top stories:
A federal jury opens deliberation today  on the sentence for the man who shot and
killed 11 Jewish worshipers at a Pittsburgh  synagogue in 2018. From member station WESA,
Julia Zenkovich reports jurors could  decide he should receive the death penalty:
"In their closing arguments Monday, prosecutors  argued that Bowers has shown no remorse for
committing the deadliest antisemitic attack  in U.S. history. They also contend that
the aggravating factors, including Bowers'  antisemitic and white supremacist beliefs,
outweigh the mitigating factors, such  as any mental health issues he may have.
Defense lawyers reminded jurors that they must  weigh mitigating and aggravating factors and
come to an individual moral judgment.  They say Bowers' tumultuous childhood
and mental illnesses should persuade the  jury to sentence him to life in prison.
"For NPR News, I'm Julia  Zenkovich, in Pittsburgh."
Police in Memphis, Tennessee, shot  and critically wounded a man who
had opened fire at the building of  a Jewish school yesterday. He had
tried and failed to get inside. No one  in the Memphis Jewish school was hurt.
Federal health officials want to find  out more about the condition known as
"Long-COVID." NPR's Will Stone reports they've
launched a handful of new studies to  test different potential treatments:
"The National Institutes of Health is opening  enrollment in four clinical trials. One is
exploring the theory that the virus somehow  persists in the body after the infection.
Patients will be given the antiviral  Paxlovid to see if that improves their
symptoms. Another focuses on brain fog and  cognitive dysfunction, leveraging web-based
brain training programs and a popular brain  stimulation method. Other trials will look at
drugs that could improve sleep problems, as well  as symptoms associated with irregular heartbeat,
dizziness and fatigue. While there are specialized  clinics for treating 'Long-COVID,' there are still
huge gaps in our understanding of its  underlying causes and how to treat it.
"Will Stone, NPR News."
Searing heat is sticking around the  central U.S. today. Heat indexes will
hover around 110 degrees from Kansas  and Missouri down to the Gulf Coast
of Alabama and Louisiana. Forecasters  say this heat will push to the east.
In China, at least 11 people have  died and dozens more are missing
amid flooding in the western suburbs  of Beijing. NPR's Aowen Cao has more:
"The intense spring has prompted Beijing to close  tourist attractions like the Forbidden City,
but the most affected areas are the city's  outer districts. Riverbeds that usually stay
dry for much of the year were overwhelmed by  downpours. Around 120,000 people in vulnerable
communities have been evacuated to school  gyms, according to state media. The city's
government announced on Tuesday that two rescue  workers were among those killed. This level of
rainfall is highly unusual for Beijing, a  city that enjoys a dry climate. However,
more and more northern regions in China  have reported floods in recent years.
"Aowen Cao, NPR News, Beijing."
This is NPR.