The Senate continues to work on legislation  to regulate artificial intelligence.
And the Centers for Disease  Control and Prevention is
urging everyone 6 months and up  to get the new COVID boosters.
Good morning. I'm Jeanine Herbst, from NPR  News, and here are today's top stories:
In Libya, 2,000 bodies have been recovered  from the eastern port city of Derna after
heavy rains caused dams to burst,  sending floodwaters into the town.
Officials say entire neighborhoods were  washed away. NPR's Ruth Sherlock has more:
"With roads cut off, um, there's very, there was  very little help getting to Derna for the 30, the
first 36 hours. Now there are responders in the  city. Faraj al-hasi, of the Libyan Red Crescent,
he's in the organization's emergency response  room, and he told me they're being inundated
with calls by people who are still stranded  in the storm debris or trapped under rubble,
and they're also looking at how to cope with  all of those that have lost their homes."
NPR's Ruth Sherlock reporting.
Libya is a country that's divided by two rival
governments and has dealt with  more than a decade of conflict.
The Senate's getting back to work on crafting  legislation that would regulate the use of AI.
NPR's Windsor Johnston reports the first  of a series of forums will be held today,
as lawmakers scramble to keep  up with the emerging technology:
"Senate Majority Leader Chuck Schumer  says today's AI insight forum is the
next step in the complicated process  of regulating artificial intelligence:
'It will affect just about every aspect of society  in major ways — both positive and negative — and
on an issue this wide-ranging and important,  we must make every good faith effort to act.'
"Schumer says members of the Senate will be  seeking input from tech pioneers, including
Elon Musk, Mark Zuckerberg and Bill Gates.  The forums, which will run through the fall,
will also hear from academics, national  security experts and civil rights leaders.
"Windsor Johnston, NPR News, Washington."
The CDC says everyone age 6 months  or older should get an updated COVID
vaccine this fall. NPR's Maria Godoy reports this
guidance follows an FDA advisory group's  recommendations on the vaccine's rollout:
"In a statement, the CDC said that vaccinating  everyone from 6 months and up with updated shots
will protect against potentially serious outcomes  from COVID illness this fall and winter. Updated
COVID vaccines from Pfizer-BioNTech and Moderna  will be available later this week. In a separate
statement, the Department of Health and Human  Services said that most Americans will still be
able to get a COVID vaccine for free. For people  with health insurance, most plans will cover the
COVID-19 vaccine at no cost. People who don't  have health insurance or who have health plans
that do not cover the cost can get a free vaccine  from their local health centers and pharmacies.
"Maria Godoy, NPR News."
You're listening to NPR News, from Washington.