A second shipment of food,  water and medical supplies
has crossed the border from Egypt into Gaza.
And Australia's prime minister is  planning to travel to Beijing next month.
Good morning. I'm Korva Coleman, from NPR  News, and here are today's top stories:
The Israel Defense Forces say they conducted well  over 300 strikes on targets in Gaza overnight
as the war between Israel and Hamas continues.  Israel says Hamas killed 1,400 people — mostly
Israelis — when the militants attacked two  weeks ago. Palestinian health authoritities
now say at least 4,600 Palestinians have  been killed in Israeli air strikes in Gaza.
A second shipment of humanitarian aid  has arrived in Gaza. NPR's Jackie Northam
reports from Jerusalem it was limited to  14 trucks with water, food and medicine:
The second convoy of aid trucks passed  through the Rafa Crossing after a long
delay. Each truck was thoroughly inspected to  make sure no weapons bound for Hamas militants
were on board. Relief workers say the supplies  are just a fraction of what's needed for the
more than 700,000 Palestinians who have fled  their homes in Northern Gaza to escape constant
air strikes by the Israeli military. On Sunday,  President Biden spoke with Israeli Prime Minister
Benjamin Netanyahu and affirmed there would be  a continued flow of humanitarian aid into Gaza.
That could change if and when an anticipated  Israeli incursion into Gaza gets underway.
Jackie Northam, NPR News, Jerusalem.
Republican congressman George Santos  will be a key vote this week as the
GOP struggles to elect a new House Speaker.  But the scandal-plagued congressman from New
York is also expected back in federal court  on Long Island. NPR's Brian Mann explains:
George Santos posted on social media that  he expects to receive the longest Speaker
ballot in modern history this week, describing  it as a historic mark for the 118th Congress.
Candidates for the speakership have so far  failed to receive the 217 votes needed to
lead the narrowly divided House, and Santos' vote  could be crucial, but if the process drags on,
Santos is also scheduled back in  federal court on Long Island Friday,
facing new felony corruption counts. Federal  prosecutors say Santos tried to rack up big,
unauthorized charges on the credit cards of his  political donors. Santos has admitted lying to
voters about much of his life's story, but denies  any criminal wrongdoing. Earlier this month,
his campaign treasurer pleaded guilty to  charges linked to her work on his campaign.
Brian Mann, NPR News.
Australia's Prime Minister, Anthony Albanese, says  he will travel to Beijing next month. NPR's Emily
Fang says he'll be the first Australian  leader to visit China in seven years:
Tensions with China escalated after Australia's  then-Prime Minister Scott Morrison called for
an independent investigation into the origins of  COVID in China in 2020, but since being elected to
power last year, Albanese's government has sought  to ease tensions with Beijing. He'll attend a
big export fair in China next month. China's  release of an Australian political prisoner,
the journalist Cheng Lei, this month,  also marked a diplomatic breakthrough.
NPR's Emily Fang.
This is NPR.