Wildfires have devastated the  historic town of Lahaina and
claimed the lives of at least 55 people in Maui.
And driverless taxis have been given the  green light to operate in San Francisco.
Good morning. I'm Windsor Johnston, with  NPR News, and here are today's top stories:
Fast-moving wildfires continue to  rage across Maui, leaving widespread
destruction in their path. The blazes have  decimated the historic town of Lahaina,
a popular destination for tourists. Tiffany  Kidder Winn owns a business there. She says
she returned to the community yesterday  to get a first-hand look at the damage:
"As I walked, though, it started getting worse  — power lines down and then started to see
smoke and, I mean, there was smoke everywhere,  but it was getting thicker, and cars burned,
and apartment complexes burned. And  the further we got onto Front Street,
the more devastating it was  — just everything leveled."
Authorities say the wildfire that engulfed  Lahaina is now 80% contained. At least 55
people have died in the fires, with  the death toll expected to rise.
Attorneys for former President Donald  Trump will be in court today in Washington,
D.C. NPR's Kristin Wright reports prosecutors in  the 2020 election conspiracy case are asking a
judge for a protective order that would seek to  prevent Trump from improperly sharing evidence:
"Special Counsel Jack Smith's team is legally  required to disclose evidence in the case to
former President Trump and his defense team.  Prosecutors are concerned Trump will reveal
sensitive information and target witnesses,  compromising the trial. Prosecutors requested
a protective order last Friday, hours after  the former president posted on his Truth Social
platform, "If you go after me, I'm coming after  you." Trump defends his comments, made the day
after his arraignment, saying a protective  order would violate his free speech. Today,
a judge is hearing arguments from both sides.  Last week, Trump pleaded not guilty to conspiring
to overturn the results of the 2020 election  and block the peaceful transition of power.
"Kristin Wright, NPR News."
A utilities commission in California has voted to
allow driverless car companies to  act like taxis in San Francisco,
but as NPR's Dara Kerr reports, they're  facing resistance from emergency responders:
"The San Francisco police and fire  departments have been vocal about
their opposition to driverless cars.  They say the vehicles have impeded
first responders' operations, running  through yellow emergency tape and
blocking firehouse driveways. Here's San  Francisco Fire Chief Jeanine Nicholson:
'Our folks cannot be paying  attention to an autonomous
vehicle when we've got ladders to throw.'
"Nicholson has been urging California's  transportation regulator to halt the growth
of driverless vehicle programs  in the city, but in a 3-1 vote,
regulators decided to allow the programs  to expand. Now, autonomous vehicles run by
Cruise and Waymo can pick up passengers  and charge a fare, just like a taxi.
"Dara Kerr, NPR News."
The 2023 Atlantic hurricane season will  likely be more active than first predicted.
That's according to the National Oceanic  and Atmospheric Administration. NPR's Jeff
Brady reports NOAA says warmer waters in the  Atlantic could fuel up to 21 storms this year:
"At the start of the summer, NOAA predicted  a near-normal number of named hurricanes and
tropical storms this year in the Atlantic.  Now, the agency projects an above-normal
level of activity. Matthew Rosencrans, with  NOAA, says warmer water is the main reason:
'The June-July sea surface temperature in  the main development region of the North
Atlantic were the warmest since 1950, at  1.23 degrees Centigrade above normal.'
"There's a global trend of rising ocean  temperatures due, at least in part,
to climate change, though scientists  are still trying to understand what's
driving the current record-breaking ocean heat.
"Jeff Brady, NPR News."
This is NPR News, in Washington.