Eight Republican presidential  hopefuls will face off tonight
in Milwaukee in the party's first primary debate.
And on Maui, officials say more than  1,000 are still unaccounted for.
Good morning. I'm Jeanine Herbst, from NPR  News, and here are today's top stories:
The first 2024 Republican presidential debate  is tonight in Wisconsin. Eight candidates are
expected to be on the debate stage in  Milwaukee for the event organized by the
Republican National Committee. Chuck  Quirmbach, with member station WUWM,
says former President Donald Trump  remains the front-runner for the party's
presidential nomination, but he won't  be taking part in this initial debate:
"Trump is skipping the Milwaukee debate  in favor of an interview with former Fox
News host Tucker Carlson. Carroll University  political science Professor Lilly Goren says
that will change things for the eight  Republican candidates who are debating:
'Some of the candidates having greater  exposure on the national level and also,
to some degree, what they may say in  regard to former President Trump.'
"The Democratic National Committee says the debate
will introduce America to an  extreme slate of candidates.
"For NPR News, I'm Chuck Quirmbach, in Milwaukee."
Officials in Hawaii say more than 1,000 people  remain unaccounted for in the aftermath of the
wildfires on Maui. The official death toll remains  at 115, as efforts continue to locate additional
human remains in the charred rubble of buildings.  NPR's Jennifer Ludden says authorities are asking
relatives of the missing to submit DNA samples  to help identify additional victims of the fires:
"The FBI is leading this effort. At  a news conference, an agent reassured
people their DNA would not be used for  anything but matching with the remains
of wildfire victims. He also said samples  from multiple family members is best. But
the fire in the historic town of Lahaina  was so intense some DNA analysis might be
difficult. Maui Police Chief John Pelletier  said they may not find everyone who died:
'When this is all said and done, realistically  — let's be honest here — we're going to have a
number of confirmed; we're going  to have a number of presumed.'
"The county did reveal the names of  eight more victims — almost all seniors.
"Jennifer Ludden, NPR News, Maui."
Ethiopia says it will work with Saudi Arabian  authorities to investigate allegations by Human
Rights Watch that Saudi border guards killed  Ethiopian migrants. Michael Kaloki has more:
"A Human Rights Watch a report claims that,  between March last year and June this year,
Saudi Arabian border guards killed hundreds of  Ethiopian migrants who tried to cross into Saudi
Arabia from Yemen. Ethiopia said it will work  alongside Saudi authorities to investigate the
allegations. Human Rights Watch claims that  the alleged killings could amount to crimes
against humanity. Saudi Arabian authorities  have previously rejected the allegations."
Michael Kaloki reporting.
This is NPR News.