A convicted Michigan school's hooter's  sentencing hearing will resume tomorrow.
And an aid group says a New Hampshire nurse  and her child have been kidnapped in Haiti.
Good morning, I'm Korva Coleman, from NPR  News, and here are today's top stories:
The heat wave is concentrating on the central  U.S. today. Heat indexes will be well into the
triple digits from Wichita to New Orleans.  Health officials are warning people to do
all they can to stay cool. Activist Sabrina Pacha  is with the group Healthy Air & Water Colorado.
She says that's harder in communities  of color, which often have fewer trees:
"In Denver, we have a neighborhood that  is 88% residents of color and just 3%
of their neighborhood has tree cover, in  comparison to another part of the city,
where just 15% of residents are of color  and they have upwards of 17% of tree cover."
Problems with heat are amplified in cities —  they're subject to something called the urban
heat island effect. Fewer trees and more asphalt  make it tougher for urban areas to cool off.
A hearing resumes tomorrow to  determine whether a convicted
Michigan school shooter will get life in  prison without parole. Lawyers for Ethan
Crumbley say he was so young at the time  of the Oxford High School shooting in 2021
that he can be rehabilitated. From member  station WDET, Quinn Klinefelter has more:
"Prosecutors described how then-15-year-old  Ethan Crumbley took a handgun bought for
him by his parents, calmly killed four  students and shot seven other people,
then waited to see the pain he'd inflicted.  They say that demands a life sentence without
the chance for parole. But the defense counters  that 15-year-old brains are not fully developed,
and Crumbley never received any mental health  care. An expert on prison rehabilitation,
Dr. Kenneth Romanowski, said juveniles convicted  of even the most heinous crimes can reform:
'Honestly, I think everybody has the  potential to change, and I think Mr.
Crumbley would be no exception to that rule,  but I think he has to make that choice.'
"Defense attorneys say crumbly himself  might also also take the stand.
"For NPR News, I'm Quinn Klinefelter, in Detroit."
A relief group in Haiti says a nurse from New  Hampshire and her child have been kidnapped
in Haiti. NPR's Joe Hernandez reports  that, last week, the State Department
urged Americans to leave Haiti because of  rising gang violence, crime and disease:
"El Roi Haiti says on its website that Alix  Dorsainvil and her child were kidnapped from
the aid group's campus outside Port-au-Prince  on Thursday. Dorsainvil is a nurse with the
organization, as well as the wife of its  founder. In a statement. El Roi Haiti said,
'Alex is a deeply compassionate and loving  person who considers Haiti her home and the
Haitian people her friends and family.' A  spokesperson for the U.S. State Department
says it has no higher priority than the safety  and security of U.S. citizens overseas and that
it's in contact with Haitian authorities. Unrest  in the Caribbean nation has worsened recently,
with a rise in kidnappings and other  violence committed by armed gangs.
"Joe Hernandez, NPR News."
This is NPR.