At least 36 people are dead as wildfires  continue to burn across the island of Maui.
And new vaccines to protect  against "tripledemic" of the flu,
COVID and RSV are expected in the next few months.
Good morning. I'm Windsor Johnston, with  NPR News, and here are today's top stories:
Catastrophic wildfires continue  to rage across the island of Maui,
killing at least 36 people and injuring dozens of  others. Hawaii Senator Mazie Hirono says hundreds
of tourists and residents in the historic  town of Lahaina were forced to evacuate:
"All of the businesses and the  10,000 or so people who live there,
in addition to the tourists, all needed, needing  to either shelter in place or be evacuated."
Helicopter pilot Richard Alston surveyed  the damage over Lahaina on Wednesday:
"It's just level — flat to the ground. Just,
just a horrible thing. Just it's,  uh, for- history, forever gone."
President Biden has approved federal resources  to help local search and rescue efforts.
State health officials are looking ahead  to the fall and to the threat of flu,
RSV and COVID-19 coming together.  NPR's Pien Huang reports people will
have new options to protect themselves this year:
"COVID cases are swelling this summer, but  health officials are more concerned about the
coming months with back to school and cooler  weather helping respiratory viruses spread.
Over the next few months, new vaccines  against flu, COVID and, for older people,
RSV are coming out to help protect people  against this "tripledemic." Dr. Anne Zink,
chief medical officer for Alaska, says  it may be best for those 60 and older
who are now eligible for an RSV  vaccine to get that shot first:
'But if someone has the resources  and ability to spread them out,
there is some data that being able to spread  them out could be beneficial to that individual.'
"Then, in general, flu and COVID vaccines can  be given together when they're out this fall.
"Pien Huang, NPR News."
Intelligence officials in Ukraine are  releasing new information about a Russian
hacking attempt. NPR's Jenna McLaughlin  reports the operation targeted military
situational awareness platforms used by Ukraine:
"Russian hackers moved closer to the front lines  with Ukraine in order to steal Ukrainian Android
tablets and spy on military operational  planning. That's according to a new report
by Ukraine's Security Services, the SBU. The  head of the SBU Cyber Department, Ilya Vityuk,
told NPR these combat information  platforms are Russia's top priority:
'Our enemy is extremely focused in  getting insight into this systems.'
Vityuk said the SBU thwarted Russia's attempts to  get full access to its military planning tools,
but the hackers did get some sensitive information
but he said that exposing Russia's tactics can  help protect its allies from similar attacks.
"Jenna McLaughlin, NPR News, Kyiv."
This is NPR News, in Washington.