Former President Donald Trump has been  indicted over his alleged efforts to
overturn the results of the  2020 presidential election.
And at least 20 people are dead and dozens more  missing after days of heavy rain in Beijing.
Good morning. I'm Korva Coleman, from NPR  News, and here are today's top stories:
Former President Donald Trump has been  indicted on four charges related to
alleged efforts to overturn the 2020  election. NPR's Jaclyn Diaz has more:
"This indictment is the third criminal case  against Donald Trump and may be one of the most
serious against the former president. This case  involves at least six co-conspirators and involves
allegations Trump and his allies interfered in  a U.S. election in an attempt to cling to power.
"Prosecutors also allege that Trump engaged with  officials in several states to spread lies that
there was election fraud. Trump's co-conspirators  have not been named by prosecutors. He's expected
at the federal courthouse in Washington, D.C.,  for his first court appearance on Thursday.
"Jaclyn Diaz, NPR News."
Vice President Harris says she's rejected  an invitation by Florida Gov. Ron DeSantis
to join a roundtable discussion. It was  to focus on Florida's new Black history
curriculum. One instruction tells Florida  middle school students that some enslaved
Black people gained skills that could  sometimes be used for their personal
benefit. Speaking in Orlando. Harris  lambasted that as "revisionist history":
"There is no roundtable, no lecture,  no invitation we will accept to
debate an undeniable fact. There were  no redeeming qualities of slavery."
Florida Gov. DeSantis accuses the  Biden administration of misinforming
people on the subject and disparaging his state.
The National Weather Service says the  dangerous heat wave persists from the
Southwest into the southern Plains  today and down to the Gulf Coast.
Heat indexes could reach 110 degrees from  eastern Texas to southern Mississippi.
At least 20 people are dead and dozens of others  are missing in flooding in China's capital,
Beijing. As NPR's Julia Simon reports,  climate change can make rain events worse:
"China is experiencing record-breaking  heat this summer — northwest China saw
temperatures of 126 degrees. Scientists from  the World Weather Attribution initiative say
this summer's heat wave is virtually impossible  without human-caused climate change — a hotter
atmosphere can hold more moisture, so  rainstorms can be more intense. Global
warming primarily comes from humans burning  fossil fuels. If humans seriously reduce
the use of fossil fuels, scientists say the  world can avoid more devastating scenarios.
"Julia Simon, NPR News."
Meanwhile, a new typhoon is lashing  southern Japan. There are reports
from Japan that one person may  have been killed by the storm.
This typhoon's current path could lead  it to hit eastern China later this week.
You're listening to NPR News.