President Biden will address the  U.N. General Assembly later today.
And Congress is up against a deadline at the end
of the month to avoid a partial  federal government shutdown.
Good morning. I'm Korva Coleman, from NPR  News, and here are today's top stories:
President Biden and Ukrainian  President Volodymyr Zelenskyy
will address the U.N. General Assembly today.
NPR's Michelle Kellerman reports Russia's  war in Ukraine will be high on the agenda:
"Biden administration officials say Russia's  war strikes at the heart of the U.N. charter,
and President Biden will reinforce that in his  speech to the General Assembly. For his part,
President Zelenskyy is trying to convince  countries that have been on the fence to
back his ideas on how the war should end —  that is, with Ukraine sovereignty intact.
The conflict has affected countries  around the world — especially those
that rely on Ukrainian grain exports. Russia  recently pulled out of a deal that allowed
Ukraine to ship food via the Black Sea. The U.N.  Secretary-General is still trying to revive that.
"Michelle Kellerman, NPR News, New York."
The Indian government has rejected allegations it  was involved in the killing of a Sikh separatist
leader in Canada. Canadian Prime Minister Justin  Trudeau made the claim in Parliament yesterday.
Sushmita Pathak reports ties between  both countries are at a historic low:
"The two countries are sparring over the  Khalistan movement, which seeks to establish
a Sikh homeland separate from India. India  considers Khalistan supporters terrorists
and accuses Canada of sheltering them. In June,  a Sikh separatist leader was shot dead in Canada,
and Trudeau accuses India's government of  being involved in it. India's Ministry of
External Affairs called the allegations absurd and  motivated. India has expelled a senior Canadian
diplomat after Canada removed a top Indian  diplomat. New Delhi has also expressed concerns
about what it calls growing interference  by Canada in India's internal affairs.
"For NPR News, I'm Sushmita Pathak, in Delhi."
Congress is working toward a critical deadline  to pass a bill that would keep the federal
government open past September 30th. NPR's  Windsor Johnston tells us House Republicans
have unveiled a stopgap funding measure; the  Democrats in both chambers are blasting it:
"Senate Majority Leader Chuck Schumer  is describing the House proposal as a
hard-right screed, accusing Republicans of  refusing to work across the aisle to come up
with an agreement. The Biden administration  and Congressional Democrats are demanding a
number of provisions that are not included in  the House bill, including additional aid for
Ukraine. Without those elements, the stopgap bill  is likely to fail in the Democratic-led Senate."
NPR's Windsor Johnston reporting.
Policymakers for the U.S. Federal Reserve open  a two-day meeting in Washington today. They're
expected to discuss short-term interest rates. The  Fed has raised rates sharply over the last year
and a half — that's because it is still trying  to get inflation down to its target rate of 2%,
but in August, inflation was  running at an annual rate of 3.6%.
You're listening to NPR News.