President Biden will walk a picket line with  members of the United Auto Workers today.
And later today, a hearing gets underway over  a doping scandal from the 2022 Winter Olympics.
Good morning. I'm Korva Coleman, from NPR  News, and here are today's top stories:
This is Day 12 of the United Auto Workers' strike  against Detroit's Big Three automakers. President
Biden plans to be in Michigan today to join  a picket line in the Detroit suburbs. NPR's
Deepa Shivaram reports the president  was invited by the head of the UAW:
"President Biden, who often touts himself  as being the most pro-union president,
says the United Auto Workers helped save the  automobile industry when it was crashing:
'And I think that, now that  the industry is roaring back,
they should ... they should participate  in the, in the benefit of that.'
"Biden's visit comes the day before former  President Donald Trump comes to visit Detroit
as well. The union endorsed Biden in 2020 but has  yet to endorse a candidate in the 2024 election.
"Deepa Shivaram, NPR News, the White House."
A union representing thousands of  hospitality workers in Nevada is
taking a strike vote today. The Culinary  and Bartenders Union is negotiating with
the Las Vegas casinos and hotels for a  new contract. No walkout is imminent.
The House is scheduled to vote on  spending bills today. The government
will partially shut down this weekend unless  Congress passes spending legislation. Some
hardline House Republicans are  blocking their own party's bills.
Authorities in Hawaii have allowed the first set  of people to return to their burned out properties
in the city of Lahaina. Most of the city on  the island of Maui was burned to the ground by
wildfires in August. At least 97 people perished.  Resident Tawny Katayama lost her family home:
"Lahaina ... it looks like a war  zone, and we are grieving, and
there are triggers everywhere,  and we're not ready for that."
The residents were offered protective equipment  to shield them from toxic dust — there's concern
that the ash could contain dangerous  substances, such as asbestos or lead.
A three-day hearing gets underway today in  Switzerland. It's expected to finally settle
a doping scandal that marred the 2022 Winter  Olympics in Beijing. NPR's Brian Mann reports,
because of the controversy, some U.S. figure  skaters still have not received their medals:
"Russian star figure skater Kamila Valieva  was found to have tested positive for a banned
substance, but she was still allowed to compete  in Beijing last year. Months of international
legal wrangling followed, leading to this week's  final hearing before the Court of Arbitration for
Sport. U.S. skater Vincent Zhou says he wanted  to be present for the hearing but was denied:
'That just adds another layer of  obscurity to, you know, you know,
what really goes on behind closed doors —  what sorts of conversations are they having,
you know, like, why don't  they want us to, to see?'
"Valieva faces a possible  multi-year suspension from
figure skating. If she and her  Russian team are disqualified,
U.S. team skaters will receive a gold medal. It's  not clear when a final ruling will be issued.
"Brian Mann, NPR News."
This is NPR.