U.S. Secretary of State Anthony  Blinken has arrived in Israel as
death tolls among Israelis and  Palestinians continue to rise.
And tensions are also high on  the Israeli-Lebanese border.
Good morning. I'm Korva Coleman, from NPR  News, and here are today's top stories:
Secretary of State Anthony Blinken has  arrived in Israel for immediate talks
with Israeli leaders. He's reiterating U.S.  support for Israel following the Hamas attack
on the country. Israeli President Isaac Herzog  is demanding other nations also condemn Hamas:
"I call upon the international  community, unequivocally:
Make clear and loud condemnation of Hamas, just as  you condemned ISIS — they are one and the same."
Israeli officials now say Hamas killed at  least 1,300 Israelis. Hamas also continues
to hold scores of people hostage. Israel is  heavily bombing Gaza. Palestinian authorities
say at least 1,200 Palestinians have been  killed in Gaza by Israeli air strikes.
Meanwhile, tensions remain high on the  Israeli-Lebanese border after exchanges
of rocket and artillery fire this week.  Many Lebanese fear their country could be
dragged into the conflict between Hamas  and Israel. Jawad Rizkallah has more:
"Hezbollah attacked a military position near the  Israeli town of Avivim with anti-tank rockets and
then fired missiles at Israeli soldiers near the  Palestinian-Israeli village of Arab al-Aramshe
this week. The Israeli army responded with  artillery and drone strikes against the
Lebanese village of Al-Dhayra, where at  least one house was destroyed. They also
hit at least two other villages. Hezbollah  has also called upon the Arab and Islamic
world to condemn the American decision to  deploy the U.S. Navy's largest aircraft
carrier to the eastern Mediterranean.  In a statement, the Lebanese militant
group said the action would not deter from  potential further confrontation with Israel.
"For NPR News, I'm Jawad Rizkallah, in Beirut."
The federal fraud case continues  against cryptocurrency mogul Sam
Bankman-Freid. The prosecution's  star witness, Caroline Ellison,
accused him of masterminding a scheme to steal  billions of dollars. NPR's David Gura has more:
"Caroline Ellison was the CEO of the  hedge fund Sam Bankman-Freid founded,
a member of his crypto-empire's inner circle,  and she Bankman-Freid's ex-girlfriend. In her
second day of testimony, Ellison detailed how  she manipulated balance sheets, allegedly at
Bankman-Freid's direction, to disguise billions  of dollars Alameda took from customers of FTX
without their knowledge. She also recounted  what happened in late 2022 amid a downturn in
the crypto market and as the relationship  between Alameda and FTX was scrutinized.
As Ellison described the collapse of Alameda  and FTX, she started to cry. It was, she said,
the worst week of her life. Bankman-Freid's  defense attorney will cross-examine her today.
"David Gura, NPR News, New York."
The House is still in recess as Republicans  try to move forward their choice to be
Speaker. Congressman Steve Scalise won  a GOP leadership election yesterday,
but he doesn't have enough Republican  votes yet to win the Speakership.
Separately, a group of House Republicans  is seeking to expel fellow GOP Congressman
George Santos. He denies charges of corruption.
You're listening to NPR News.