Former President Donald Trump is expected to  turn himself in to authorities in Georgia today.
And on Maui, a high school in  Lahaina is fully reopening today.
Good morning. I'm Jeanine Herbst, from NPR  News, and here are today's top stories:
Former President Donald Trump is  expected to turn himself in to
the Fulton County Jail later today. Georgia  Public Broadcasting's Stephen Fowler reports
Trump faces 13 felony counts for an alleged  effort to overturn Georgia's 2020 election:
"In some ways, Trump will be like every  other defendant who stepped foot into the
Fulton County Jail: He'll be formally arrested,  fingerprinted and processed after being charged
last week. But the former president,  who is under Secret Service protection,
also was expected to have a booking photo taken  — the first one in the four different indictments
he's received in the last few months. After  upstaging the GOP presidential debate last
night by refusing to attend, Trump's visit to  Atlanta is expected to dominate headlines again,
with his arrival expected to coincide with  evening prime time television viewing hours.
"For NPR News, I'm Stephen Fowler, in Atlanta."
One high school fully re- or opens  today in the Maui town of Lahaina,
where at least 115 people died in a  wildfire earlier this month. Meanwhile,
NPR's Jennifer Ludden reports more places  are offering temporary housing to survivors:
"In addition to hotels, the county says landlords  and property owners across the state have stepped
up — they've offered 900 houses, apartments  or rooms for wildfire survivors to rent. A new
Maui bus route also starts Thursday; it will  take evacuees between hotels and a shopping
mall — a lot of people lost their cars in the  fire, and they have found travel difficult."
NPR's Jennifer Ludden reporting.
Schools across the country are leaving  millions — perhaps billions — of federal
dollars on the table. That's money that could  help tens of millions of children, including
kids with disabilities. Emily Harris reports  on the findings of a new NPR investigation:
"The money comes from Medicaid, which  covers many health needs for students with
disabilities and students from low-income  families. Last year, schools got a total
of $6.6 billion. Medicaid officials say they  could be getting much more, but many schools
say the reimbursement process has been too  cumbersome to be worthwhile. Now, Medicaid
has simplified things. Deputy Administrator Dan  Tsai hopes this will get more money into schools:
'You're talking about things on the  order of magnitude of billions.'
"First, though, states have to update  their Medicaid policies. So far,
at least 22 states have at  least partially done so.
"For NPR News, I'm Emily Harris."
The head of the Wagner mercenary group, Yevgeny  Prigozhin's name was found on the passenger
list of a plane that crashed with no survivors  north of Moscow, but there is no confirmation
that he is dead. Russian state media says 10  bodies were recovered — this just months after
Prigozhin launched a mutiny against Russia's  military leadership. President Vladimir Putin
relies on the Wagner group to supplement  Russian troops in his war against Ukraine.
Republican presidential hopefuls gathered in  Milwaukee for the first Republican presidential
primary debate carried by the Fox News  Channel. They sparred over a number of issues,
including the economy, abortion and former  President Donald Trump's alleged efforts
to overturn the 2020 election.  NPR's Sarah McCammon has more:
"Trump refused to attend the debate, saying  his solid lead in primary polls made his
participation unnecessary. Moderators asked  the candidates to weigh in on indictments
he's facing in four jurisdictions  and his actions leading up to the
January 6th Insurrection. Former Vice  President Mike Pence said in a debate
on the Fox News Channel he would support  Trump if he's the Republican nominee,
even if he's convicted, but Pence said he could  not support Trump's request on January 6th:
'He asked me to put him over the Constitution,  and I chose the Constitution — and I always will.'
"Eight Republicans met the criteria to participate  in the Milwaukee debate, which includes signing a
pledge to support the eventual nominee. The city  also will host the GOP convention next summer.
"Sarah McCammon, NPR News, Milwaukee."
I'm Jeanine Herbst, and you're  listening to NPR News, from Washington.