Good morning. I'm Louise Schiavone,  NPR News. Today is Tuesday,
August 22nd, and here are today's top stories:
Officials on the Hawaiian island of Maui have  released two more names of victims from the
historic blaze there two weeks ago. The death  toll stands at 115, up one from yesterday. 35
victims have been identified. At the same time,  more than 800 people on Maui remain unaccounted
for. The question is did they perish or have  they not checked in with family or friends?
President Biden and First Lady Joe Biden toured  the wildfire devastation on Maui yesterday,
later pledging sustained federal support at a  community event at the Lahaina Civic Center.
Hawaii Senator Mazie Hirono  says the loss is profound,
especially considering the modest  local government coffers on Maui:
"It is going to be a lot of money, and  this county has suffered tremendous
losses — because their county budget  doesn't cover anything of this magnitude."
The blaze on Maui was the  deadliest wildfire in U.S. history.
Recovery efforts are underway in Southern  California in the aftermath of flash floods
and mudslides brought on by Tropical Storm Hilary.  From member station KVCR, Madison Aument reports:
"The resort town of Palm Springs and  surrounding desert cities east of Los
Angeles received some three inches of  rain. The area typically sees roughly
5 inches a year. Shane Reichardt is  a spokesman for Riverside County,
that includes Palm Springs. He says, now that the  sun is out, the county is assessing the damage:
'We're such a large county, with 7,300 square  miles, that there's a lot of area to check.'
"He says flooding is still blocking  roads in Palm Springs, and the storm
knocked out the 911 emergency call system  there on Sunday night. Emergency officials
also have their eye on debris flows in  areas where wildfires burned recently.
"For NPR News, I'm Madison  Aument, in San Bernardino."
The FDA has approved the first RSV vaccine to  be taken during pregnancy. The shot will protect
newborn babies during their vulnerable first  months of life. NPR's Sydney Lupkin has details:
"The FDA has approved a new tool in the  arsenal against RSV. The virus causes mild,
cold-like symptoms in most people,
but can be serious in young children and older  adults. Pfizer studied the vaccine in more than
7,000 pregnant women across 18 countries.  The vaccine was 82% effective at preventing
severe disease in infants during their first  three months of life, and 70% effective in the
first six months. Dr. Scott Roberts, from the  Yale School of Medicine, says it's good news:
'I think a lot of us in the medical community  are facing the winter ahead with some optimism
and enthusiasm that we now have several  options that are coming down the pipeline.'
"Last month, the FDA also approved a  monoclonal antibody shot for babies
up to 24 months old. It's made by AstraZeneca.
"Sydney Lupkin, NPR News."
This is NPR.