At least 106 people are dead after  the devastating wildfires in Maui.
And federal officials are easing  some water restrictions along
the Colorado River after a wet winter.
Good morning. I'm Jeanine Herbst, from NPR  News, and here are today's top stories:
Survivors of the deadly wildfires in Maui  that destroyed the city of Lahaina are
finding communications are still difficult,  with intermittent power and unreliable cell
service. At least 106 people are dead.  Many residents say they are worried about
scammers and major developers coming in  to buy up the land as they try to rebuild
their lives. Hawaii Gov. Josh Green says  he will come down hard on anyone who does:
"If someone behaves in a predatory fashion towards  one of the people that are suffering right now,
who have lost their loved ones or  lost their home, lost their rental,
and they try to buy land out from under them,  you can be sure I will not be allowing anyone
to build or rezone or do anything of that sort  if they've taken advantage of anyone here."
President Biden says he will visit the area soon.
On Capitol Hill, Senate Majority  Leader Chuck Schumer is marking
the first anniversary of President  Biden's major legislative achievement,
also known as the Inflation Reduction  Act. NPR's Deirdre Walsh has more:
"Schumer acknowledged that it will take a while  for the impact of the climate and health care
bill to sink in with voters, but he says, 'The  best is yet to come.' The Senate majority leader
argues that talking about the economic benefits  of the law, which Democrats passed on their own,
will show a major contrast between  the two parties in the 2024 election:
'And I think the contrast
between the Republicans and us is glaring —  we are investing, they are investigating.'
"Schumer says that what he calls the  largest climate action bill in history
will lower costs and expand the middle class  by creating new jobs in the energy sector,
but Republicans say Americans  are still paying higher prices,
and that inflation will hurt  Democrats next fall at the ballot box.
"Deirdre Welsh, NPR News, Washington."
Federal officials are easing cutbacks on some  users of the Colorado River after a wet winter
gave the nation's largest reservoirs a boost.  For member station KUNC, Alex Hager has more:
"Arizona and Nevada will still face some cutbacks  to their water supplies in 2024, but they'll be
less steep than this year's — that's according  to the Bureau of Reclamation — but pressure is
still on policy makers to reduce water demand  over the long term. Brenda Burman directs
the Central Arizona Project, which brings  Colorado River water to the Phoenix area:
'All of us who rely on the river, who  rely on our amazing infrastructure,
have to be able to come to the table  and show how they can live with us.'
"Human-caused climate change is shrinking  the amount of water in the river,
and the seven states that use it are scrambling to
find ways to cut back on demand from  cities and farms across the arid West.
"For NPR News, I'm Alex Hager,  in Fort Collins, Colorado."
In Women's World Cup soccer, England is heading to
the finals to play Spain this weekend,this  after beating Australia this morning, 3-1.
You're listening to NPR News.