Good morning. Today is Tuesday,  September 5th. I'm Korva Coleman,
from NPR News, and here are today's top stories:
The former leader of the far-right group the  Proud Boys will be sentenced today in federal
court in Washington. Enrique Tarrio  is facing decades in prison for his
role in the January 6th attack at the U.S.  Capitol. NPR's Jaclyn Diaz says Tarrio is
among five members of his group convicted  of seditious conspiracy or other crimes:
"Prosecutors say Tarrio and his lieutenants  saw themselves as foot soldiers of the right.
He was convicted, along with four other members  of the Proud Boys, back in May. On January 6th,
2021, Tarrio wasn't at the Capitol; rather,  he was at a hotel room outside of Washington,
D.C. Prosecutors say, from this position,  Tarrio urged his members to take control
of the U.S. Capitol. Prosecutors  are seeking 33 years for Tarrio,
but the judge is likely to give him less —  some of Tarrio's co-defendants have received
lengthy prison sentences but shorter  than what the government had requested.
"Jaclyn Diaz, NPR News."
The Texas State Senate will open  an impeachment trial today against
Attorney General Ken Paxton. He is accused  of several counts of corruption. Paxton
says he is innocent and derides the  case as a politically motivated sham.
Leaders of the United Auto Workers say they  are pressuring the Big Three automakers to
agree to huge changes in their contracts  — UAW workers are seeking a 46% pay raise,
a 32-hour workweek with full pay and the return
of traditional pensions. UAW President  Shan Fain says the union is determined:
"If we don't get our share of social and  economic justice, I can guarantee you one thing:
Come September 14th, we're going to take  action to get it by any means necessary."
Officials with General Motors, Ford and  Stellantis say the union's demands are
unreasonable. They cite international competition  as the industry changes to electric vehicles.
China's top leader, Xi Jinping, will not be  among the world leaders who are attending
the Group of 20 summit in New Delhi,  India, this coming weekend. Instead,
China is sending its premier. Beijing has  not given an explanation for this snub,
but NPR's Emily Fang reports  why Xi will be absent:
"China's Foreign Ministry said Premier Li Qiang,  widely seen as a Xi ally, will attend the summit.
Xi Jinping has not said why he won't attend  the meeting, which will be hosted by India's
Narendra Modi. Xi does have more than enough  to do at home, however — critical sectors of
the Chinese economy have been tanking, namely real  estate and construction, and that's dragged down
economic growth and worsened business sentiment  in the country. And China-India relations have
gone from bad to worse — soldiers from the two  countries had a fatal brawl near a contested
border in 2020, and since then, China and India  have expelled all of each other's journalists.
"Emily Fang, NPR News, Taipei."
You're listen to NPR News from Washington.