Good morning. Today is Tuesday,  October 24th. I'm Korva Coleman,
from NPR News, and here are today's top stories:
An elderly woman taken hostage by Hamas  says she "went through a nightmare" and
is relieved to be free. NPR's Peter  Kenyon reports her release comes as
the Israeli military continues to  attack Hamas positions in Gaza:
85-year-old Yocheved Lifshitz spoke outside the  Tel Aviv hospital where she's being treated. She
said she was taken on a motorcycle as they  raced away and was hit with a wooden pole.
Her watch and jewelry were stolen. After  a long walk through underground tunnels,
she said they came to a hall, where they  were guarded. She said it seemed like Hamas,
"prepared for this for a long time." The  Hamas-run Ministry of Health in Gaza says
nearly 5,800 people have been killed thus  far, including more than 2,300 children.
Peter Kenyon, NPR News, Jerusalem.
French President Emmanuel Macron  is visiting Israel. He met with
Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu today,
who warns Israel's fight against Hamas is a  battle with which the West must also engage:
The test for the West and for civilization is  Hamas. If Hamas emerges victorious, we will all
lose. Europe will be endangered. Everyone will  be endangered. Civilization will be endangered.
Macron expressed solidarity with Israel:
This fight against terrorism is obviously matter
of existence for Israel, but it's  matter of existence for all of us.
Macron is calling on the international coalition  fighting ISIS to also include fighting Hamas.
Very limited amounts of relief aid are  entering Gaza. Nearly 60 trucks with water,
food and medicine have gotten into the enclave in  the past few days many have been delayed in Egypt,
waiting for permission to cross.  Israel continues to maintain its
blockade of Gaza. It means a cut-off of fuel  needed to power water pumps and hospitals.
House Republicans will meet behind  closed doors today to try again to
nominate a speaker. NPR's Susan Davis reports  there are now eight candidates in the race:
Majority Whip Tom Emmer enters the race with  the strongest initial position to win. The
Minnesota representative is the No. 3-elected  Republican in leadership and, prior to that,
ran the House Republicans' campaign operation when  the party won the majority in the 2022 midterms.
But current leaders have struggled in this Speaker  fight, and Emmer is not as close of an ally to
former President Donald Trump as some of his  colleagues would like. Also running: Mike Johnson,
of Louisiana — he's also in leadership  and has close with party base activists;
Georgia's Austin Scott is making a second run for  the job, and Florida's Byron Donalds. Donalds is
a junior lawmaker but part of the Freedom Caucus  and would be the first Black speaker if elected.
Susan Davis, NPR News, Washington.
Former President Donald Trump is expected to  return to his civil fraud trial in New York
today. A key witness is his former lawyer Michael  Cohen. Trump's denied allegations that he wrongly
inflated the value of some of his properties.  Cohen is expected to testify against him.
This is NPR News.