Without a Speaker of the House, work  in Congress grinds to a halt today.
And classes have been called off  at Morgan State University today,
in Maryland, after a shooting on campus  last night left five people injured.
Good morning. I'm Korva Coleman, from NPR  News, and here are today's top stories:
Work in the House of Representatives grinds  to a halt today now that Congressman Kevin
McCarthy has been forced out as  Speaker. From member station KVPR,
Joshua Yeager reports McCarthy says  he won't run for speaker again:
"McCarthy kept his head held high during an
hourlong news conference following his  unprecedented ouster as House Speaker:
'So I may have lost a vote today,  but as I walk out of this chamber,
I feel fortunate to have  served the American people.'
"His firing was prompted by a stopgap bill  to continue funding the government with
support from Democrats. A defiant  McCarthy said he had no regrets:
'You know, if you have to lose for something,
I will always lose for the country —  it is a much better battle to have.'
"Any successor will face a deeply divided  Congress and a costly shutdown looming weeks away.
"For NPR News, I'm Joshua Yeager, in Bakersfield."
In a hypothetical two-way matchup for  president in 2024, President Biden and
former President Donald Trump are in a  dead heat. That's according to the latest
NPR/PBS/NewsHour/Marist poll. As NPR's Danielle  Kurtzleben reports, third-party candidates would
make for a more complicated race, but it's  not clear if they would spoil it either way:
"The poll also matched up Biden and Trump  with a generic Green Party candidate,
a generic Libertarian candidate and another  generic third-party candidate. In that race,
around one in five Americans chose a  third-party candidate or were undecided.
However, that still left Trump and Biden with  roughly even shares of the vote. Of course,
Trump hasn't won the GOP nomination, but the  poll also found him much more popular among
the GOP electorate than his primary opponents: 74%  of GOP voters view Trump favorably; the only other
GOP candidate seen favorably by even a majority of  GOP voters was Florida Gov. Ron DeSantis, at 58%.
"Danielle Kurtzleben, NPR News."
Baltimore police say someone opened fire last  night on the campus of Morgan State University,
in Maryland. Five people were hurt. Baltimore
Police Commissioner Richard Worley says  their injuries are not life-threatening:
"We did not locate the suspect at this time,
um, the scene remains active, and  we are working alongside our many
federal law enforcement partners to piece  together everything exactly happened."
Classes have been cancelled  today at Morgan State University.
This year's Nobel Prize in chemistry is being  shared by three scientists: Moungi Bawendi,
Louis Brus and Alexei Ekimov. They're being  cited for their discoveries among the smallest
particles in nanotechnology. These so-called  quantum dots spread their light from LED lamps,
and they help guide surgeons when they remove  tissue with tumors in them. The Nobel Prize
in literature will be awarded tomorrow. The  Nobel Peace Prize will be announced on Friday.
You're listening to NPR news.