I'm Louise Schiavone, NPR News.  Today is Monday, August 21st,
and here are the stories we're looking at:
On Maui, the wildfire-stricken town of Lahaina is  bracing for rain from Tropical Cyclone Fernanda.
NPR's Jennifer Ludden reports that water runoff  could carry toxic chemicals into the ocean:
"The seaside town of Lahaina is now a hazardous  site after the intense blaze two weeks ago left
ash laced with lead, asbestos and other  chemicals. To keep rains from washing
toxic debris into the ocean, officials have  wrapped up storm drains. The Coast Guard has
also put large booms around eight pipes that  drain into the ocean, says Lt. Trenton Brown:
'It's like a sponge, and what it does  is it stops that oil, absorbs it,
and allows the water and other things to go by.'
"Officials also warn of possible mudslides  and advise swimmers to avoid any brown water.
"Jennifer Ludden, NPR News, Maui."
President Biden is expected to arrive  on fire-ravaged Maui today. He issued
a statement on the social media platform  X, formerly known as Twitter, that he and
First Lady Jill Biden plan to meet with the first  responders of Lahaina, spend time with families
and community members, and see firsthand  what the community will need to recover.
Post-Tropical Cyclone Hillary is bringing  intense rainfall to Northern Mexico and
Southern California. NPR's Julian  Simon reports that areas east and
southeast of Los Angeles are seeing flash floods:
"The Eisenhower hospital in Rancho Mirage,  California, is having to move the water out
of the Emergency Department. An employee tells  NPR the ambulance bank was flooded and that,
as of Sunday evening, the hospital is running  on a backup generator. There's also flooding
and road closures in other areas east of Los  Angeles, like Palm Springs and Indio. The Los
Angeles Unified School District is closing  schools Monday. Southern California also
experienced an earthquake on Sunday, but there  are no immediate reports of damage. Because of
the storm, the LA mayor has warned residents  to stay home and avoid getting in their cars
and on the roads. Rainfall flooding  is the No. 1 killer in hurricanes.
"Julian Simon, NPR News, Santa Monica."
The BRICS Summit of developing economies,  including Brazil, Russia, India,
China and South Africa, begins in Johannesburg  on Tuesday. Kate Bartlett reports South Africa
has sought to assure a West worried about a  new power block that it isn't picking sides:
"South Africa President Cyril Ramaphosa  addressed the nation ahead of the summit,
stressing the democracy, which also has  strong relations with China and Russia,
would not "be drawn into a contest between  global powers." He said South Africa,
which has remained neutral on Ukraine,  supported peace and was working towards
ensuring children who were removed from  their homes were returned to their families."
Kate Bartlett reporting.
This is NPR.