A former advisor to former President Donald Trump
has been convicted on criminal  charges of contempt of congress.
And record rainfalls swept across Hong Kong  and parts of southern China on Thursday night.
Good morning. I'm Korva Coleman, from NPR  News, and here are today's top stories:
President Biden arrives in New Delhi in a few  hours to attend the Group of 20 summit. India
holds the rotating G-20 presidency this year,  and India is looking to prove itself as a world
leader. But Sushmita Pathak reports in New Delhi,  some of the preparations have drawn criticism:
"New Delhi has gotten a makeover in recent  weeks, with decorative lights and water
fountains embellishing its streets. Posters about  the G-20 are on every corner. But as the city
gears up to welcome world leaders, officials  have evicted slum dwellers and removed hawkers
and beggars from the streets. Green sheets pitched  on wooden poles along key roads hide the homeless
from view. This has prompted criticism from  opposition parties and civil society groups
who say India wants to be a voice for the global  south but is hiding its own problems with poverty.
The summit is also expected to inconvenience Delhi  residents — food delivery is barred in many parts,
traffic is heavily restricted, and dozens  of trains and flights have been canceled.
"For NPR News, I'm Sushmita Pathak, in Delhi."
Former Trump aide Peter Navarro has been convicted  on two counts of criminal contempt of Congress.
He was charged with defying a subpoena from the  House select committee investigating the January
6th insurrection. NPR's Dustin Jones reports  Navarro could spend up to two years behind bars:
"It took less than four hours for a  federal jury to issue a guilty verdict,
after only hearing from three witnesses,  none of whom came from the defense.
After the verdict was issued, Peter  Navarro said he would be exonerated:
'I am willing to go to prison to settle this issue  — I'm willing to do that, but I also know that the
likelihood of me going to prison is relatively  small because we are right on this issue.'
"Navarro had tried to have the charges  dismissed, citing executive privilege,
but a judge ruled against that argument  last week. He is the second former Trump
aide to be convicted for failing to  cooperate with a congressional subpoena.
"Dustin Jones, NPR News."
Flash floods caused by unprecedented rain and  downpours have caused widespread disruption in
Hong Kong and in parts of southern China.  We have more from the BBC's Celia Hatton:
"Hong Kong recorded its highest rainfall since  records began — more than 15 centimeters in a
single hour. Millions have been forced  to shelter in Hong Kong and the Chinese
mainland's neighboring hub of Shenzhen. In Hong  Kong, roads were turned to rivers, metro stations
and shopping malls have been flooded with water.  More than 80 people sought hospital treatment,
and several needed to be pulled from their  cars. All schools have been closed and the
authorities are urging employers to  allow their staff to remain at home."
The BBC's Celia Hatton reporting.
You're listening to NPR.