Gaza's Health Ministry says more  than 6,500 people have been killed
in Israeli air strikes, which continued overnight.
And the House of Representatives is expected to
vote today on Congressman Mike  Johnson's bid to be Speaker.
Good morning, I'm Korva Coleman, from NPR  News, and here are today's top stories:
The Israeli military says it carried out  more than 400 air strikes on Gaza yesterday,
and the bombing did not stop overnight. NPR's  Peter Kenyon reports the Hamas-run Gaza Health
Ministry says more than 6,500 people have been  killed there, and 2,700 of them are children:
The Hamas-run Interior Ministry says the,  "massive air bombardment" pounded Gaza overnight,
contributing to the unprecedented death  toll since the Hamas attack on Oct. 7.
The attacks came as Gaza continues to suffer  severe shortages of food, water and medicine,
despite the arrival of some truckloads  filled with humanitarian aid. Separately,
the IDF said it thwarted an assault by a  group of Hamas militants who came ashore on
an Israeli beach, just north of Gaza. Israel  responded with air, sea and ground forces.
Peter Kenyon, NPR News, Jerusalem.
President Biden may make comments today about  the war between Israel and Hamas militants.
He'll also be welcoming the Prime Minister  of Australia to the White House. Australian
leader Anthony Albanese will also be the guest  of honor tonight at a White House State Dinner.
The House of Representatives is expected to  vote today to elect a Speaker. Republicans
have nominated Louisiana Congressman Mike  Johnson. NPR's Deirdre Walsh reports he's
the fourth nominee in three weeks  the GOP hopes can get the gavel:
Johnson won the House GOP vote after multiple  ballots and just hours after another Republican,
Tom Emmer, from Minnesota, was nominated but was  forced to withdraw because he couldn't lock down
the votes for a full House vote. Johnson  vowed he'll get the House back to work:
We're going to serve the people of  this country — we're going to restore
their faith in this Congress. ... You're  going to see a new form of government,
and we are going to move this quickly.  This group here is ready to govern.
Johnson needs the support of almost all  House Republicans. If he gets the votes,
the new Speaker starts with immediate challenges:  He'll need to negotiate a deal to avoid a
government shutdown next month and navigate a  large foreign aid package for Israel and Ukraine.
Deirdre Walsh, NPR News.
The Senate has voted 98-0 to approve President  Biden's nominee to be the chief of the Federal
Aviation Administration. Michael Whitaker  is a former FAA Deputy Administrator.
An off-duty Alaska Airlines pilot is facing  scores of federal and Oregon state charges.
Joseph Emerson tried to cut off a jet's  engines mid-flight on Sunday. He was
riding in the cockpit with the crew on duty,  who overpowered him before he could do it.
Aubrey Gavello was aboard that flight too,  and she says the passengers were rattled:
No fight, no commotion, um, just nervous  passengers — but quietly nervous.
Emerson, meanwhile, faces 83 accounts  of attempted murder in Oregon. Police
in Portland released information yesterday  about the off-duty pilot. They say Emerson
told them he'd taken hallucinogenic  mushrooms two days before the flight.
It's NPR.