Iran claims to have had no involvement in  Hamas' attack on Israel over the weekend.
And two candidates for the next Speaker of the
House will make their pitch to  Republicans tonight in a forum.
Good morning. I'm Korva Coleman, from NPR  News, and here are today's top stories:
Israel says it has regained control of areas  of southern Israel that were attacked by Hamas
militants. The Israeli military says it  has found hundreds and hundreds of bodies
of Hamas militants who died fighting inside  of Israel — that's a sign of the size of the
attack that was launched Saturday morning.  Israeli officials say at least 900 Israelis
have been killed in the attack. Israel has been  heavily bombing Gaza. Palestinian officials say
at least 700 Palestinians have been killed and  say about a third of them are women and children.
Iran's Supreme Leader says the Islamic  Republic had no involvement in the Hamas
attack. NPR's Peter Kenyon reports Ayatollah  Ali Khamenei did voice praise for what he
called "irreparable" military and  intelligence defeat for Israel:
"In a televised address — his first since the  attack — Ayatollah Khamenei said Tehran was not
involved. He did, however, hail the operation,  saying, 'we kiss the hands of those who planned
the attack on the Zionist regime.' The Iranian  mission to the United Nations made a similar
comment, saying Tehran firmly stands behind  the aspirations of the Palestinian people
but refuted claims that it had a role in the  operation. Western and mid-east intelligence
officials said Iran had provided training, money  and other assistance to Palestinian militants.
"Peter Kenyon, NPR News, Istanbul."
The White House says that, later today,  President Biden will speak about the
situation in Israel. The administration  says at least 11 Americans have been
killed in the attack. There have been many  demonstrations in the U.S. in support of
Israel. That includes a prayer gathering held by  Orthodox Jews in Brooklyn, New York, last night.
There were rallies in support of Palestinians,
as well. In New York, police separated  opposing groups using metal barricades.
House Republicans are trying to elect a new  Speaker after Kevin McCarthy was removed
from the job last week. NPR's Susan Davis  reports the two declared candidates will
make their pitch to Republicans tonight in a  forum that's being held behind closed doors:
Majority Leader Steve Scalise and Judiciary  Chairman Jim Jordan are the only two declared
candidates in the race. Neither lawmaker is  close to the near-unanimous level of support
needed for Republicans to elect a new Speaker  on the House floor. And while the ousted Kevin
McCarthy initially ruled out trying to reclaim  the gavel, he indicated in a press conference
this week that he would if he could get the  votes. One of McCarthy's leading detractors,
Florida's Matt Gates, said on social media  that it was time for Republicans to 'move
forward without McCarthy.' Republicans plan to  hold a secret ballot election on Wednesday and
they could move to the House floor for a public  vote depending on the outcome of that election.
"Susan Davis, NPR News, Washington."
You're listening to NPR News.