Hundreds gathered to hold a  vigil Sunday for the victims
of a mass shooting in Florida over the weekend.
And crews are working to contain  wildfires in multiple Louisiana parishes.
Good morning. I'm Windsor Johnston, with  NPR News, and here are today's top stories:
The victims of the mass shooting  in Jacksonville, Florida,
were remembered during a vigil yesterday.  Will Brown, of member station WJCT, reports
a white gunman opened fire at a Dollar General  store on Saturday killing three Black people:
"Hundreds gathered under oak trees in an  oft-forgotten neighborhood Sunday to remember
Angela Carr, AJ Laguerre and Jerrald Gallion. The  three were killed in an act of racial violence on
Saturday afternoon in a Dollar General store  in Jacksonville's Grand Park neighborhood. The
Reverend John Guns, of St. Paul Missionary  Baptist Church, knew Gallion for years:
'And I wept in church today like a baby  because my heart is tired. We are exhausted.'
"The Jacksonville Sheriff's Office says the  shooter, 21-year-old Orange Park resident
Ryan Christopher Palmeter, obtained the  weapons used in the racist rampage legally.
"For NPR News, I'm Will Brown,  in Jacksonville, Florida."
Emergency crews are working to  contain a series of wildfires
burning in multiple parishes across  Louisiana. The blaze broke out near
the Texas border nearly a week ago.  Aubri Juhasz, of member station WWNO,
reports the fire has burned an estimated 60,000  acres and destroyed more than 20 structures:
"Multiple communities in and around Beauregard  Parish are under mandatory evacuation orders
as firefighters chase flames that keep changing  direction. Sheriff Mark Herford says the parish
has the resources it needs to keep fighting the  fire, but he doesn't yet see the end in sight:
'I don't really see us being able to to completely
have this situation in hand until  we get some good, long rain.'
"The fire is just one of many burning  in the area and across the state.
Louisiana's unusual number of fires  this year — more than 400 this month
alone — have been caused by severe  drought and record-breaking heat.
"For NPR news I'm Aubri Juhasz, in New Orleans."
Secretary of Commerce Gina Raimondo is  taking part in a series of meetings in
China this week. The talks in Beijing  and Shanghai come as trade relations
between the U.S. and China have hit historic  lows. Raimondo says she's looking forward to
having constructive discussions on  areas for potential cooperation:
"It's a complicated relationship. It's  a challenging relationship. We will,
of course, disagree on certain issues,
but I believe that we can make progress  if we are direct, open and practical."
Raimondo says the economic relationship  between the U.S. and China is one of the
most significant in the world, with the two  nations sharing more than $700 billion of trade.
This is NPR News, in Washington.