Hurricane Idalia is making its  way toward Florida's Gulf Coast.
And a 20-year-old Ugandan man could  face the death penalty after being
charged with so-called "aggravated homosexuality."
Good morning. I'm Windsor Johnston, with  NPR News, and here are today's top stories:
The Biden administration has released a list of  medications that will be subject to the first
ever price negotiations by Medicare.  The list includes 10 prescriptions,
including blood thinners Eliquis and Xarelto,  and the diabetes drug Jardiance. The provision
that allows Medicare to negotiate the price of  prescription drugs for people over the age of 65
was part of President Biden's signature Inflation  Reduction Act that he signed into law last year.
Hurricane Idalia is gaining strength  as it heads toward the Gulf Coast of
Florida. NPR's Greg Allen reports the storm  is expected to make landfall tomorrow as a
category 3 hurricane with wind  speeds of 120 miles per hour:
"The National Hurricane Center says Idalia  is moving north through the Gulf of Mexico
on a track that's likely to bring it ashore  Wednesday in Florida's Big Bend area. That's
a relatively undeveloped part of the state,  but Florida Governor Ron DeSantis says people
should be prepared for impacts along most of  the Gulf Coast, from Tampa Bay to Panama City:
'This thing comes in at category three, it's going  to knock over trees, it's going to knock over
power lines, it's going to cause an interruption  in service, so just be prepared for that.'
"Idalia is also forecast to bring a storm  surge as high as 12 feet in some areas
and flooding from heavy rains as it moves  through Florida, Georgia and the Carolinas.
"Greg Allen, NPR News, St. Petersburg."
Former White House Chief of Staff  Mark Meadows testified in Atlanta
yesterday as part of an effort to  move racketeering charges against
him to federal court. Georgia Public  Broadcasting's Stephen Fowler has more:
"Meadows is one of 19 people,  including the former president,
under indictment for allegedly violating  Georgia laws by taking various steps to
overturn the 2020 election there. In a court  hearing seeking to move his charges to federal
jurisdiction and ultimately seek to dismiss  them, Meadows defended actions like organizing
a call between Trump and Georgia's Secretary  of State. He argued that, as Chief of Staff,
those things were part of his job responsibilities  advising the president, but prosecutors alleged
Meadows engaged in political activity outside  of his role and violated state law in the
process. The move comes as arraignments for  all 19 defendants is set for next Wednesday.
"For NPR News, I'm Stephen Fowler, in Atlanta."
A 20-year-old man in Uganda has been charged  for so-called "aggravated homosexuality."
NPR's Emmanuel Akinwotu reports it's an  offense that carries the death penalty:
"We managed to get in touch  with his lawyer, Justine Ballia,
and she said he's the first person to be charged  for 'aggravated homosexuality.' She told us he's
being charged for having, 'sexual contact  with someone with a disability of the same
sex.' We don't know what the disability  is or really much else about the case."
NPR's Emmanuel Akinwotu reporting.
This is NPR.