Hurricane Idalia has made landfall along Florida's  Gulf Coast as a "major" Category 3 storm.
And a new survey shows labor  unions remain popular in the U.S.
Good morning. I'm Kristin Wright, with NPR  News, and here are today's top stories:
Hurricane Idalia has made landfall along  Florida's Gulf Coast. In the past hour,
sustained wind speeds decreased slightly,  downgrading it to a Category 3 storm, but storm
surge and catastrophic flooding remain a serious  threat to communities. Elliot Tritto, of member
station WUFT, reports hospitals in Florida are  ready to receive a possible influx of patients:
"Hospitals in North Central Florida are  preparing for what could be a lot of patients
with storm-related injuries. Matt Shannon is  an emergency physician with the University
of Florida. He says it's happened with every  hurricane affecting the area. In his experience,
the wave of patience comes not  during the hurricane, but after:
'Most people will have the good sense to stay  home and button down the hatches. It's, uh, we
tend to get large emergency department volumes  the day after those storms pass through.'
"He says to take precautions, like wearing  eye protection during post-storm cleanup. For
anyone riding out the storm, he says to use  common sense, wait for it to blow over and,
if you have a small injury, take care of it at  home, but if it's a major injury, call 9-1-1.
"For NPR News, I'm Elliot Tritto, in Gainesville."
Today, President Biden is expected to announce  $95 million in federal assistance to improve
Hawaii's power grid and strengthen its  ability to withstand future disasters.
Devastating wildfires claimed the lives of at  least 115 people on Maui earlier this month.
Commerce Secretary Gina Raimondo is  wrapping up talks in China. Raimondo is
the latest Biden administration official  to visit China in a bid to ease tense
trade relations. Secretary Raimondo  spoke to reporters in Shanghai today:
"I explained very clearly that, as  a Commerce Secretary, it's my job to
both protect what we must — to protect our  technology — and to promote where we can."
A new Gallup survey shows labor unions remain  popular in the U.S. NPR's Andrea Hsu reports:
"The survey actually found public approval of  unions has fallen a few percentage points from a
year ago — it's now at 67%, which is still higher  than it's been for most of the past half-century.
Support for union workers also appears strong —  72% of respondents said they sympathize more with
Hollywood writers than with Hollywood studios; 75%  said they'd side with the United Auto Workers over
the auto companies. At the same time, a sizable  minority of people question what good unions do —
one out of three said unions mostly hurt the U.S.  economy. The survey results come as health care
workers at Kaiser Permanente and auto workers have  threatened to strike if their demands are not met.
"Andrea Hsu, NPR News."
Former Proud Boys leader Enrique  Tarrio is expected to be sentenced
today for his role in the January  6th attack on the U.S. Capitol.
You're listening to NPR News.