Secretary of State Anthony Blinken is  visiting several Arab states today to
discuss the current conflict  between Israel and Hamas.
And Steve Scalis is dropping out  of the race to be House Speaker.
Good morning. I'm Korva Coleman, from NPR  News, and here are today's top stories:
Israel is telling Palestinians in northern Gaza to  leave immediately and go to the southern part of
the enclave. They've been given 24 hours to  do so. It's feared that an Israeli military
ground assault will soon begin. Hamas leaders  have told Palestinians not to go anywhere.
U.N. officials and other human rights groups are  urgently warning that a million Palestinians are
under the Israeli warning, and it's impossible  to move that many people in so short a time.
Separately, Hamas leaders are claiming  that Israeli airstrikes have killed 13
Israeli and foreign hostages. The claim has not
been confirmed. Hamas has abducted  scores of people out of Israel.
Secretary of State Anthony Blinken  is making a swing through several
Arab states today to discuss the  conflict. NPR's Michelle Kellerman
reports he wants the leaders to  urge Hamas to free the hostages:
"Secretary Blinken started his day with  a closed-door meeting with Jordan's King
Abdullah followed by talks with the Palestinian  Authority President, who has a residence in
Amman. The State Department says Blinken  discussed the 'horrific' Hamas terrorist
attacks on Israel and the efforts to secure  the release of all hostages and prevent the
conflict from widening. That's a message he's  also bringing to Qatar, Bahrain, Saudi Arabia,
the United Arab Emirates and Egypt. At that last  stop, Blinken will also discuss efforts to open up
a humanitarian corridor out of Gaza, especially  for Palestinian Americans trapped there.
"Michelle Kellerman, NPR News, Amman."
Defense Secretary Lloyd Austin  arrived in Tel Aviv a few hours
ago. He's meeting with Israeli leaders to  discuss U.S. security assistance to Israel.
Republican Congressman Steve Scalise is  quitting the race to become the next Speaker
of the House. NPR's Giles Snyder reports he  didn't have the votes from other Republicans:
"Congressman Scalise spoke  to reporters after emerging
from a closed-door meeting with  his House Republican colleagues,
saying he is withdrawing after they failed  to come together around his nomination:
'Clearly, not everybody is there, and there's  still schisms that have to get resolved.'
"The House has been without of Speaker  since the ouster of Kevin McCarthy,
leaving the chamber unable to take action on  the government spending bills needed to avoid
a shutdown in November and facing pressure  to support Israel in the war with Hamas.
"Giles Snider, NPR News."
Philadelphia police say one officer has  been killed and another wounded after they
tried to interrupt thieves breaking into  a car at the airport. Interim Philadelphia
Police Commissioner John Stanford says  they're looking for the assailants:
"There are multiple suspects that were  involved in this situation, so, um,
still trying to get some additional information  on those other individuals that were involved so
we can get that information out  as quickly as we possibly can."
Philadelphia authorities say another  person was taken to the hospital,
rather, hospital separately and died.
This is NPR.