Jim Jordan says he plans to  move ahead with a third vote
on his bid to become House Speaker later today.
And Israel has ordered thousands of people
to evacuate a town near its  northern border with Lebanon.
Good morning. I'm Korva Coleman, from NPR  News, and here are today's top stories:
Ohio Congressman Jim Jordan is pushing ahead  with his bid to become Speaker of the House.
he's failed twice this week, and he lost  more Republican lawmakers in the second
round of voting than he did in the first.  Jordan doesn't seem to be bothered by that:
We picked up a few, we lost a few — I think  the ones we lost can come back — so, uh, look:
There's been multiple rounds of votes for Speaker  before, um, we all know that. I just know that we
need to get a Speaker as soon as possible so  we can get to work for the American people.
A third vote could happen this morning, but  the opposition to Jordan from some Republicans
seems entrenched. Many members have complained  that Jordan and his supporters have bullied and
threatened them, their staffs and their families.  Jordan has said he opposes the harassment.
Israel is ordering thousands of people to  evacuate a town near the northern border with
Lebanon. Cross-border attacks from Hezbollah  are continuing. NPR's Peter Kenyon reports
Israel also launched more strikes in Gaza,  hitting a Greek Orthodox Church compound:
Israel began evacuating a town not far from the  Lebanese border — the second such evacuation order
to be issued and the latest sign that a ground  invasion of the Gaza Strip may be imminent.
Israel's Defense Minister told troops to be  prepared to see Gaza from the inside. Palestinians
in Gaza, meanwhile, report heavy air strikes  in Khan Yunis and the Interior Ministry says
an air strike late Thursday at a church compound  left a large number of dead and wounded. The IDF
said it was looking into the reported strike  on the Greek Orthodox Saint Porphyrius Church.
Peter Kenyon, NPR News, Jerusalem.
Palestinians stuck in southern Gaza still  cannot access aid. Many trucks carrying water,
food and medicine are waiting across the border,  in Egypt. The U.N. Secretary-General is at the
border crossing urging officials in Israel and  Egypt to allow aid to go through. President
Biden said earlier he secured promises from  both countries to allow aid to enter Gaza.
The Justice Department says former President  Donald Trump is not entitled to blanket
immunity from criminal prosecution.  NPR's Carrie Johnson reports this
claim is from the federal case alleging  Trump interfered in the 2020 election:
Prosecutors working for Special  Counsel Jack Smith say there's no
legal or historical support for the idea  that former presidents should be shielded
from accountability for their crimes. The  Justice Department is urging a judge to
reject Trump's bid to dismiss four felony  charges against him in a Washington, D.C.,
Court. Trump says he simply tried to protect  the integrity of the last presidential election,
but prosecutors said he led a conspiracy to  overturn the election results and keep himself
in power despite the will of the voters. Judge  Tanya Chutkan will resolve the issue. Trump may
be positioning for an appeal to the Supreme Court,  which could delay the trial, set for March 2024.
Carrie Johnson, NPR News, Washington.
This is NPR News.