The search continues for the suspect  in Wednesday's mass shootings in Maine.
And Israeli forces conducted  another raid on northern Gaza
overnight as U.N. officials say fuel  shortages are crippling relief efforts.
Good morning. I'm Korva Coleman, from NPR  News, and here are today's top stories:
The search has continued through the night  in Lewiston, Maine, for Army reservist Robert
Card. He's considered the prime suspect in  Wednesday's mass shootings. NPR's Brian Mann
reports there have been no confirmed sightings  of him and the community remains in lockdown:
A small army of police descended on one  farmhouse last night outside Lewiston,
but no arrests were made, and Card remains  on the run. He has been charged with murder
following Wednesday's shooting at a  bowling alley and nearby bar that left
18 people dead. This week's violence  caused Maine Congressman Jared Golden,
a Democrat, to reverse his opposition to  banning military-style assault weapons:
To the people of Lewiston, I ask  for forgiveness and support as I
seek to put an end to these terrible shootings.
Legislation that would reinstate  the ban on military-style assault
rifles has been stalled in Congress for years.
Brian Mann, NPR News, Lewiston, Maine.
Israel says it conducted another brief raid into  northern Gaza overnight. The Israeli military says
it targeted Hamas militants in response  to Hamas attacks nearly three weeks ago.
The Israeli blockade of Gaza  continues the United Nations
says its relief aid to Palestinians  is collapsing. U.N. official Philippe
Lazzarini says relief workers need  fuel badly and that's been cut off:
A few days ago, I warned that we will  not be able to continue our humanitarian
operation if we do not get the fuel supply. My  warning still stands. Over the last few days,
UNRWA has drastically limited its consumption  of fuel, but this came at a cost — our team
had to make tough decision that  no humanitarian workers should do.
Gaza health officials now say more than  7,300 Palestinians have been killed in
Israeli military attacks. Israel says  Hamas killed more than 1,400 people,
mostly Israelis, when militants  attacked on October 7th.
Embattled Congressman George Santos will be back  in federal court today. From member station WNYC,
Brigid Bergin reports the New York  Republican is facing 10 new fraud charges:
He's accused of conspiring with his former  campaign treasurer to file false reports with
the FEC that inflated his fundraising numbers,  including a fictitious half-million dollar loan
Santos claimed to make to his own campaign  when he only had $8,000 in his bank account,
according to prosecutors. He's also accused of  stealing his donors' credit card information and
attempting to make thousands in charges.  Some he masked as campaign donations and
others he funneled to his personal bank  account. Santos pleaded not guilty to 13
earlier charges at an arraignment in May,  and he continues to say he will not resign.
For NPR News, I'm Brigid Bergin, in New York.
This is NPR.