On Maui, the death toll has risen to at least 111.
And Texas is suing Planned Parenthood for  millions of dollars in Medicaid payments.
Good morning. I'm Jeanine Herbst from, NPR  News, and here are today's top stories:
The death toll from the Maui fires has  risen to at least 111, with the number
expected to grow in the coming days. As the  island undertakes the long road to recovery,
leaders say it's important to also make  sure the economy stays healthy and,
as NPR's Jason DeRose reports, that  means keeping tourist numbers up:
"When the fires broke out last week,  state and island officials immediately
urged tourists not to come, but it's  since become clear that most of the
damage — although severe — is contained  to the western part of Maui. More than
half the island's residents have jobs in some  way related to the tourism industry. Christian
Galapon’s aunt works as a housekeeper at a  Maui resort. She lost her home in the blaze:
'You know, people were asking her, like,  "Well, you just lost everything, like,
why'd you clock into work?" And she was,  like, "I still need to make money." '
"Last year, close to 3 million tourists visited  the island and spent nearly $5.7 billion."
"Jason DeRose, NPR News, Maui."
Planned Parenthood is awaiting a  ruling in a major lawsuit. Texas
Tech Public Media's Sarah Self-Walbrick  reports that the state of Texas is suing
Planned Parenthood for millions  of dollars in Medicaid payments:
"Texas tried to block Planned Parenthood from  getting Medicaid funds in 2015. That didn't happen
until 2021. Now, Planned Parenthood estimates it  could have to pay more than a billion dollars. It
could lead to more clinic closures in Texas. Susan  Manning is general counsel for Planned Parenthood:
'Many of the health care center patients  are women, people with low incomes and
people from other communities who have  historically faced barriers to care.'
"Conservative judge Matthew Kaczmarek, who  has made several high-profile rulings in
abortion-related cases, has not said  when he will decide in this case.
"I'm Sarah Self-Walbrick, in Lubbock."
In California, retailers are struggling as  several flash mobs rush into luxury stores and
rob them. One of the latest was last weekend, at a  Nordstrom, when more than 30 masked people rushed
into the store, broke display cases and made  offer with around $300,000 worth of merchandise.
Governor Gavin Newsom provided additional funds  to establish a retail theft task force, and that,
police say, led to the arrest of dozens of  people wanted in several thefts at different
stores in a two-day operation in Bakersfield.  California Highway Patrol Chief Rodney Ellison:
"During these two days of operations, CSP  investigators arrested over 50 suspects
for charges related to retail theft and  recovered nearly $60,000 in product."
Police say some of the theft rings  are being organized on social media.
This is NPR News.