The head of Maui's embattled Emergency  Management Agency has resigned.
And a new federal report says 2023  could be one of the hottest on record.
Good morning. I'm Jeanine Herbst, from NPR  News, and here are today's top stories:
Maui's Emergency Management administrator has  resigned a day after defending his decision not
to use the island's siren system during  the deadly wildfires. Herman Andaya says
he doesn't regret his decision because  he says the sirens are mainly used for
tsunamis. He says people would have headed to the  mountains, into the fire. Residents dispute that.
Meanwhile, the burn zone in Lahaina  is toxic. Officials are worried about
asbestos and lead because of the  age of the homes and businesses,
along with other toxic chemicals in the ash  and debris. NPR's Gabriel Spitzer has more:
"The biggest danger comes from ingesting  or breathing in the toxic chemical,
so that means that the really acute risks go  way down once the fire is out and the smoke is
dissipated. But lots of the emissions start  out as airborne particles and smoke end up
settling back down into ash and soot and they  cling to surfaces they run off into the water,
and that means people could be exposed  over and over for a really long time."
NPR's Gabriel Spitzer.
At least 111 people died. About  1,000 are listed as missing.
The National Oceanic and Atmospheric  Administration says this year could
be one of the hottest in recorded  history. NPR's Seyma Bayram has more:
"Last month marked the hottest July since 1850.  South America, Africa and Asia saw record warm
temperatures. Arizona, New Mexico, Florida and  Maine also experienced their hottest July on
record. Now, about 30% of the U.S. is experiencing  drought, says NOAA climatologist Karin Gleason:
'Drought conditions expanded or  intensified across much of the
Deep South and parts of the Southwest, as well  as the Northwest and extreme Northern tier.'
"Scientists say most of the U.S. will continue  seeing above normal temperatures through November.
"Seyma Bayram, NPR News."
North Carolina's Democratic governor  will soon decide whether to veto
sweeping elections legislation  approved this week by the state's
Republican-dominated Legislature. From  member station WUNC, Rusty Jacobs has more:
"The GOP bill would eliminate a three-day grace  period for counting mail-in ballots postmarked
by Election Day. Republicans say that would  boost voter confidence in Election Day results,
but Democrats in the North Carolina  General Assembly note the grace period
was established in 2009 through bipartisan  legislation and that claims of widespread
voter fraud are baseless. State Rep. Robert  Reeves worries eliminating the grace period
could result in otherwise valid votes getting  tossed due only to unreliable postal service:
'We are making it harder  for people to have a voice.'
"Gov. Roy Cooper is likely to veto the bill,
but Republicans have the legislative  super-majority to override it.
"For NPR News, I'm Rusty Jacobs,  in Durham, North Carolina."
You're listening to NPR News.