New Jersey Sen. Robert Menendez is scheduled  to appear in federal court this morning.
And as Hollywood's writers return to work  today, the actors' union's strike continues.
Good morning. I'm Korva Coleman, from NPR  News, and here are today's top stories:
New Jersey Democratic Sen. Robert Menendez  is scheduled to appear in federal court this
morning. For member station WNYC, Nancy Solomon  reports he faces charges of bribery and corruption
"The New Jersey senator is expected to plead not  guilty along with his wife and three businessmen.
He's charged with helping a New Jersey halal  meat business corner the market in Egypt by
supporting U.S. arms sales to the Egyptian  government. Prosecutors allege they found more
than $500,000 in cash, much of it stuffed into  envelopes and hidden in the Menendezes' home.
The senator says he's innocent and that the cash  was money he took out of the bank to have on hand
in an emergency. Gov. Phil Murphy and Sen. Cory  Booker have called for Menendez to step down.
"For NPR News, I'm Nancy Solomon,  in Maplewood, New Jersey."
The House has voted to pass  a procedural vote that opens
debate on some long-term spending  bills for the federal government,
but that debate won't come fast enough to  stop a looming government shutdown late
Saturday night. The Senate didn't wait — senators  overwhelmingly passed a short-term spending bill,
but House Speaker Kevin McCarthy says he'll  put forward his own bill in a couple of days.
Israelis will soon be able to travel to  the United States without getting a visa.
This comes after years of negotiation  and Israeli steps to make it easier
for Palestinian Americans to travel to  Israel. NPR's Michelle Kellerman reports:
"In recent months, the U.S. has been monitoring  Israeli pledges to treat all U.S. citizens
equally, including Palestinians and other  Arab Americans who have faced restrictions
and harassment at Israeli borders. U.S. officials  point out that all Americans can now go through
Ben Gurion Airport to enter Israel or to travel  to Israeli-occupied Palestinian territories,
and the U.S will continue to monitor this, even as  Israel officially joins the visa waiver program.
The U.S. is now updating its immigration  procedures for Israelis and expect that,
by Nov. 30, Israelis will be able  to come to the U.S without a visa.
"Michelle Kellerman, NPR News, Washington."
The Writer's Guild of America's  strike against Hollywood studios
is over. Union members must still vote  on whether to ratify their new contract,
but the union leadership voted to approve the  deal. Members are allowed to return to work.
However, the actors' union, SAG-AFTRA,  is still on strike against the Hollywood
studios. Some members joined a picket line  outside Netflix' offices in Los Angeles:
"We're ready. The strike is not over. SAG-AFTRA...
"We are still here. We are on strike. We have  yet to receive a contract from the AMPTP."
"What he said!"
A note: SAG-AFTRA represents most of NPR's
journalists but are governed  under a different contract.
This is NPR.