Good morning. Today is Monday,  September 11th. I'm Korva Coleman,
from NPR News, and here are today's top stories:
The death toll in Morocco has soared to  more than 2,100 people following Friday's
devastating earthquake. NPR's Lauren Frayer is in  Marrakesh, just north of the quake's epicenter:
"The biggest thing you notice is people  sleeping out doors — lots of people,
even if their home survived Friday's initial  quake, the aftershocks keep hitting, and so
you see people just running out of buildings all  of the time and many are too scared to re-enter
at all, and so every inch of green space, like  highway medians, are covered with sleeping bags."
NPR's Lauren Frayer in Marrakesh, Morocco.
It's been 22 years since Al-Qaeda terrorists  hijacked four planes and crashed them in the
eastern U.S. President Biden is returning  from Asia. He'll commemorate the day by
giving a speech in Anchorage. First Lady Jill  Biden will lay a wreath at the Pentagon. Vice
President Harris will attend ceremonies at the  World Trade Center, in New York. Her husband,
Second Gentleman Doug Emhoff, will attend  the remembrance in Shanksville, Pennsylvania.
For member station WITF, Rachel  McDevitt reports the hijackers
who crashed in Pennsylvania were  the only ones to miss their target:
"Recordings from the flight illustrate  how the 40 passengers and crew members
tried to take back control of the  plane, which was likely headed toward
the U.S. Capitol building. It crashed in a  former strip mine in western Pennsylvania,
killing all on board. The remembrance ceremony  in Shanksville includes a reading of the names
of the victims along with a bell-ringing that  will coincide with the exact time of the crash,
10:03 a.m. Rabbi Jeffrey Myers, who survived  the Pittsburgh synagogue shooting, will offer a
moment of reflection. The day's ceremonies wrap  up with a public wreath-laying at the memorial.
"For NPR News, I'm Rachel  McDevitt, in Harrisburg."
The impeachment trial of Texas's suspended  attorney general is entering its second week.
Ken Paxton faces 20 charges, and Texas  state senators will decide his fate.
The Texas Newsroom's Sergio Martínez-Beltrán  reports Paxton has influenced national policy:
"Ken Paxton rose to prominence in Texas, but as  the state's attorney general, he's made a name for
himself on a national level: He's challenged  the Biden administration on immigration,
federal spending and abortion, and he's  used former President Trump's legacy to do
it — according to the Dallas Morning News, of 20  policy challenges Paxton launched against Biden,
17 were filed in front of Trump-appointed judges.  Many of these lawsuits have successfully stalled
the implementation of Biden's policies. Paxton  has been suspended as attorney general since May.
If he's convicted by the Texas Senate,  Paxton would be removed from office.
"For NPR News, I'm Sergio  Martínez-Beltrán, in Austin."
Officials with agribusiness corporation  Archer-Daniels-Midland say there's been
an explosion at one of its plants in Decatur,
Illinois — that's less than 200 miles  south of Chicago. Several workers have
been hurt and hospitalized. There's  no word on the cause of the blast.
This is NPR.