A federal judge in Texas has again  struck down the DACA program.
And crews continue to search for bodies in  Morocco after last Friday's deadly earthquake.
Good morning. I'm Nora Raum, with NPR  News, and here are today's top stories:
A federal judge in Texas has again struck  down a program that protects undocumented
immigrants brought to the U.S. illegally  as children. From member station KERA,
Stella Chávez reports the latest  ruling blocks efforts to codify the
policy known as DACA — Deferred  Action for Childhood Arrivals.
"U.S. District Judge Andrew Hanen previously  declared the DACA program unlawful two years
ago. His latest order is in response to  a request from nine Republican-led states
to find the Biden administration's  efforts illegal and end DACA. Hanen's
decision keeps deportation and work permit  protections in place for the nearly 600,000
current DACA recipients, but new applications  can't be processed. The Biden administration
is expected to appeal and the case will  likely return to the U.S. Supreme Court.
"I'm Stella Chávez, in Dallas."
The Senate held a closed-door meeting yesterday  to hear from the nation's big biggest technology
executives on artificial intelligence. Majority  Leader Chuck Schumer had organized the conference,
saying everyone agreed the government  has a role in the oversight of AI:
"Our work is just beginning — we  need to have more of these forums,
and we need to get our committees working  on different parts of legislation because,
again, to not act would be something  that, something we want to avoid."
There apparently was no agreement yesterday  on what government regulation would look like.
In Morocco, authorities say there is no hope of  finding anyone else alive after last Friday's
earthquake. NPR's Eleanor Beardsley reports  rescue crews are still searching for bodies:
"58-year-old Brahim Agoudahid weeps as  he describes the wonderful life in his
village of Imi N'Tala before the earthquake.  The indigenous Berber village perched in the
rocky Atlas Mountains got tourists from around the  world. Now, Imi N'Tala is a scene of devastation
and wreckage after part of the mountain sheared  off and crushed it. On this day, rescue teams
with dogs were able to extract a few bodies from  the rubble after hours of digging. Within minutes,
they were placed back into the ground next to  the ruined village as men prayed and women wept.
"Eleanor Beardsley, NPR News, Morocco."
Rescue teams in the Libyan city of Derna are  searching for people still missing after a huge
flash flood Sunday night. The Associated Press  reports at least 5,100 people have died and
thousands more are missing and feared dead as a  result of Storm Daniel. Aid workers say the flood
destroyed the center of the densely populated  city and that there are bodies everywhere.
You're listening to NPR News, from Washington.