A chance of storms this weekend could bring much
needed relief from the heat  to Phoenix-area residents.
And Ukrainian forces say they have  liberated a key village in southern Ukraine.
Good morning, I'm Korva Coleman, from NPR  News, and here are today's top stories:
Excessive heat is smothering about  180 million people in the U.S.,
from the southwest to the northeast. It could  reach 113 degrees today in Phoenix. Tom Frieders,
of the National Weather Service, says  the city is setting heat records:
"That continues with temperatures  continuing to be forecast to be
above 110 into the first half  of the weekend. We do have, uh,
increased risk of thunderstorms as we progress  through the weekend into early next week."
Those storms could lower the  Phoenix temperature below 110
degrees for the first time in about a month.
President Biden is poised to sign an executive  order today that changes part of the U.S. military
justice system. The prosecution of serious  military crimes will now be transferred to
independent military attorneys. That includes the  handling of sexual assault cases. The prosecution
decisions will be taken away from victims'  commanders. The White House says the changes
are part of a bipartisan military justice  reform effort to better protect victims.
The 114th National Convention of the NAACP  opens today in Boston. For member station WGPH,
Paris Alston reports about  10,000 people will attend:
"Boston last hosted the NAACP convention  in 1982. National board member and regional
administrator Michael Curry says this year's theme  — "thriving together" — is about tackling issues,
such as voter suppression and affirmative  action while celebrating by culture:
'We will have thousands of people who will  experience Boston, so I'm excited excited
to have them immerse themselves in the history  of this city, and we have business to do here.'
"Vice President Kamala Harris, former Secretary of
State Hillary Clinton and rapper Meek Mill  are scheduled to speak at the convention.
"For NPR News, I'm Paris Alston, in Boston."
Ukraine says it has liberated a key village in the  south as its forces continue a counteroffensive to
push Russian forces out of Ukrainian land.  NPR's Joanna Kakissis has more from Kyiv:
"Ukrainian soldiers who liberated the village of  Staromaiors'ke hold the Ukrainian flag and say
'Glory to Ukraine.' President Volodymyr Zelenskyy  posted the video to his social media account with
the message 'Our South. Our guys!' Staromaiors'ke  is north of the occupied port city of Berdyans'k,
on the Sea of Azov. The capture of this village  brings Ukraine closer to one of its main
counteroffensive goals: to reach the Azov Sea and  cut off Russia's land route to occupied Crimea.
That would make it very difficult for Russia  to resupply its troops. But Russia has heavily
fortified positions in the south, and Ukrainian  officials say they don't expect quick progress.
"Joanna Kakissis, NPR News, Kyiv."
You're listening to NPR News, from Washington.