Prosecutors are seeking a protective  order today against former President
Donald Trump in his election interference case.
And more gay and bisexual  men can now donate blood.
Good morning. I'm Nora Raum, with NPR  News, and here are today's top stories:
The Justice Department is asking a judge  to issue a protective order against former
President Donald Trump. The DOJ says it's  seeking to prevent Trump from disclosing
evidence related to the four-count indictment  against him stemming from Trump's alleged
efforts to try to overturn the results of the  2020 election. NPR's Joe Hernandez reports:
"In their motion for the order, federal  prosecutors pointed to Trump's history of
making social media posts about legal matters  against him, including a post he made on Truth
Social Friday in which he wrote that he'd go  after anyone who went after him. Trump's attorney,
John Lauro, slammed the idea of a protective  order in an interview on ABC's 'This Week':
'What the Biden administration is trying to do is  prevent the press from learning about exculpatory
and, and helpful information — evidence —  that the people have a right to know about.'
"Trump's attorneys wanted more time to respond to
the Justice Department's proposal  but the judge denied that request.
"Joe Hernandez, NPR News."
The judge ordered the Trump team tp  file an answer by 5 p.m. Eastern Time.
A trio of federal voting rights lawsuits  is heading to trial today in Galveston,
Texas. Houston Public Media's Andrew Schneider  reports the combined case is the first major
trial of its kind since the Supreme Court upheld  a key clause of the Voting Rights Act in June:
"The three lawsuits charge Galveston  County with racial discrimination,
violating Section 2 of the Voting Rights Act.  The county is nearly half Black and Latino.
One of the county's four voting districts used  to be made up of a majority of Black and Latino
residents. In 2021, the Republican-led County  Commissioners Court redrew its map to split the
non-white population across all four districts,  so they do not comprise a majority anywhere,
and now County Commissioner Stephen Holmes, who  is Black and a Democrat, is far more likely to
lose his re-election bid next year if the map  is allowed to stand. Lawyers for the county
say the new map was partisan, which the U.S.  Supreme Court has allowed, and not racial.
"For NPR News, I'm Andrew Schneider, in Houston."
New guidelines from the Food and Drug  Administration take effect today, allowing
more gay and bisexual men to donate blood. Nick  de la Canal, with member station WFAE, reports:
"The previous rules were intended to protect  blood recipients from HIV, but they were called
discriminatory by many advocates. Under the new  rules, only people who've had anal sex with new
or multiple partners or take HIV prevention  drugs will be asked to wait three months
before donating. The agency says it will keep  monitoring the safety of the blood supply."
Nick de la Canal reporting.
Three people were killed when two  helicopters collided in Southern
California yesterday. They were carrying  fire crews fighting a blaze. The crash
sparked another fire, which has been extinguished.
This is NPR News.