Questions continue to swirl around a deadly  explosion at a Gaza hospital this week.
And after two days and two ballots,
Ohio Congressman Jim Jordan still doesn't  have the votes to become Speaker of the House.
Good morning. I'm Korva Coleman, from NPR  News, and here are today's top stories:
President Biden is said to make a national  address tonight from the Oval Office. He's
expected to propose a significant aid package  to support Israel and its war against Hamas and
further aid to Ukraine as it fights Russia's  invasion. This comes as the president is also
pledging $100 million in humanitarian aid  to Palestinians in Gaza and the West Bank.
The president and the U.S. intelligence  community do not believe, at this point,
Israel was responsible for a deadly explosion  at a Gaza hospital this week. The blast killed
hundreds of people. But as NPR's Greg Myre  reports, there's still a great deal of
uncertainty surrounding the blast, and Israelis  and Palestinians continue to blame each other:
There are photos, videos and eyewitness  accounts of the huge explosion at the
al-Ahli Arab Hospital, but there's not yet  clarity on who's responsible. The blast dug
a relatively small hole in the hospital's  parking lot, and the hospital did not suffer
structural damage — that suggests a smaller  weapon was used. Israel says it was a rocket
from a Palestinian faction that was directed  at Israel but misfired. Palestinians insist the
blast was part of Israel's ongoing bombing  campaign. President Biden says he believes
the Israeli version, though U.S. officials say  they're still gathering additional information.
Greg Myre, NPR News, Washington.
After two days and two ballots, Ohio  Republican Congressman Jim Jordan still
doesn't have the votes to be elected Speaker  of the House. NPR's Deirdre Walsh reports his
opponents say he'll lose more support  if he pushes for a third vote today:
Republican resistance to Jordan's bid  for Speaker appears to be hardening
or even growing. It's been 16 days since  California Rep. Kevin McCarthy was ousted,
and the House is still frozen — it can't  function until a Speaker is elected.
Calls to give the temporary Speaker,  Patrick McHenry of North Carolina,
powers to allow votes on bills are growing.  McHenry says, for now, his role is limited:
My role here is to be determined, but I've  constructed that as narrowly as the rules
say I should, and we can't transact  business until we elect a Speaker.
Jordan's GOP opponents warn tactics of  his allies to pressure them for votes are
dangerous. Two members who voted against  Jordan say they received death threats.
Deirdre Walsh, NPR News.
The National Hurricane Center  is watching Hurricane Norma,
off Mexico's Pacific Coast. Hurricane specialist  John Cangialosi says Norma is powerful:
It's the Category 3 — maximum winds are near  120 mph — and it's to the south of the southern
portion of the Baja California Peninsula — it's  about 450 miles south-southeast of Cabo San Lucas.
Meanwhile, hurricane forecasters say Tropical
Storm Tammy is in the Atlantic Ocean  and could soon turn into a hurricane.
This is NPR.