President Volodymyr Zelenskyy  travels to Washington today
as Congress weighs whether to  approve more aid for Ukraine.
And the Senate has confirmed a new  Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff.
Good morning. I'm Korva Coleman, from NPR  News, and here are today's top stories:
Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelenskyy is in  Washington, D.C., today to meet with President
Biden. He's asking for sustained U.S. military  aid to help Ukraine resist Russia's invasion.
NPR's Windsor Johnston tells us Zelenskyy will  also visit congressional leaders on Capitol Hill:
"House Speaker Kevin McCarthy is expected to  meet with Zelenskyy, but he has no plans to
provide the Ukrainian leader with a forum to make  a direct appeal to lawmakers for additional aid.
"On the Senate side, Majority Leader Chuck Schumer  has organized a meeting with the entire chamber.
"Speaking at the United Nations this week,  Zelenskyy said, without continued support,
Russia will expand its fight within Ukraine."
NPR's Windsor Johnston reporting.
The Senate has voted overwhelmingly to confirm  a new Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff:
Air Force General C.Q. Brown is the second  Black officer to hold the post. As NPR's Greg
Myre reports, the Senate action circumvented  a monthlong blockade by a Republican senator:
"In a distinguished career, General Brown  has served as a combat pilot and as Chief
of the Air Force for the past three years.  However, Alabama Republican Tommy Tuberville
blocked the confirmation of Brown and hundreds  of other military officers who would normally
be approved in large batches. Tuberville objects  to a Pentagon policy that helps military members
travel to receive abortion care if they face  local restrictions. To get around Tuberville,
Senate Majority Leader Chuck Schumer brought  Brown's nomination to a full Senate vote. He
was confirmed 83-11. Brown replaces General Mark  Milley, who steps down at the end of the month.
The only other Black officer to be Chairman  of the Joint Chiefs was General Colin Powell.
"Greg Myre, NPR News, Washington."
India has suspended visa services for  Canadian citizens indefinitely. There
are escalating tensions over the murder of  a Sikh leader in Canada. Sushmita Pathak
reports Canada claims India was involved in  the killing, a charge that New Delhi rejects:
"The form that handles Indian visa applications  in Canada said the service has been suspended due
to operational reasons. India has also issued an  advisory for its citizens in Canada, especially
the large student population, urging them to  remain vigilant as the diplomatic row worsens.
"Canada's government is investigating  India's connection to the murder of a
separatist Sikh leader, Hardeep Singh Nijjar.  India has strongly condemned the allegation.
"Both countries have expelled top diplomats.
"Calls for a Sikh nation-state separate from  India have been growing among the large Sikh
diaspora in Canada. India considers its supporters  terrorists and accuses Canada of sheltering them.
"For NPR News, I'm Sushmita Pathak in Delhi.
You're listening to NPR News.