A suspect in a riverfront brawl in Montgomery,
Alabama, over the weekend has  surrendered to authorities.
And President Biden continues his three-day swing  through the West today with a stop in New Mexico.
Good morning. I'm Nora Raum, with NPR  News, and here are today's top stories:
In Montgomery, Alabama, one of three  suspects charged with misdemeanors
following a riverfront brawl on Saturday that  went viral has surrendered to authorities.
The others are expected to be in custody  soon. The city's mayor is confident the
altercation won't affect tourism. Troy  Public Radio's Kyle Gassett reports:
"Videos of a Black co-captain of a riverboat being  beaten by and fighting with white passengers from
a pontoon boat have been viewed millions of times.  Montgomery's first Black mayor, Stephen Reed,
says he doesn't see long-term negative effects  from the attention the incident has received:
'People can separate, uh, you  know, a few bad apples, uh,
carrying on from an entire community, and  so we expect that, but we also know that we
have to continue to do things each and every  day for our citizens and our residents here.'
"Tourism is a major revenue generator for the  city, which has both civil rights landmarks
and museums and monuments built  by the Equal Justice Initiative.
"For NPR News, I'm Kyle Gassett,  in Montgomery, Alabama."
Voters in Ohio have rejected an effort to make  it harder to change the state's constitution.
Republicans proposed the threshold for  an amendment be approved be raised and
that proponents meet stricter requirements  to place a proposed change on the ballot.
The rejection means a referendum on the  November ballot to enshrine rights to an
abortion in the Ohio Constitution will  need a majority of the vote to pass.
President Biden visits New Mexico today.  Alice Fordham reports he's expected to
highlight investments in clean energy.  Member station KUNM's Alex Fordham reports:
"National Climate Adviser Ali Zaidi  told reporters about Air Force One that,
in New Mexico, people would get a chance to  see a 'manufacturing renaissance' brought
about by the administration's actions,  including the Inflation Reduction Act.
Zaidi mentioned a new plant manufacturing wind  towers in the city of Belén and the SunZia line,
a transmission project set to deliver primarily  renewable energy from New Mexico to Arizona and
California. New Mexico's state government is  working toward a statewide renewable energy
standard of 50% by 2030, but in the last few  years, fossil fuel extraction has ramped up,
and last year, it was the second-largest  crude oil producing state, after Texas.
"For NPR News, I'm Alice Fordham, in Albuquerque."
A judge in Los Angeles has sentenced rapper  Tory Lanez to 10 years in prison for shooting
hip-hop star Megan Thee Stallion  in the foot during an argument.
Attorney Jose Baez says his client is  being punished for being a celebrity:
"I have seen cases — vehicular homicide  and other cases where there's death — and
the person still gets less than 10 years."
He says they'll appeal the sentence.
Hurricane Dora is passing well off the Hawaiian  Islands, but its winds have grounded firefighting
helicopters. Crews are battling several  wildfires. Hundreds of homes have been evacuated.
This is NPR News.