Former President Donald Trump's civil business  fraud trial gets underway today in New York.
And more than 75,000 health care workers at Kaiser
Permanente are preparing to  go on strike later this week.
Good morning. I'm Korva Coleman, from NPR  News, and here are today's top stories:
Former President Donald Trump says he will  be at the state courthouse today in New York
City. He faces civil fraud charges that  threaten some of his most iconic assets,
including Trump Tower. NPR's Brian Mann reports:
"Donald Trump and his associates, including  his two sons, are accused of systematically
overvaluing their properties by more than $2  billion in order to secure financing and make
deals. In one case, New York Attorney General  Leticia James says they inflated the square
footage of a building by 300%. Last week, state  judge Arthur Engoron issued a summary judgment,
finding Trump did violate accounting rules  Engoron described Trump's valuations of his
properties in financial statements as fantasy.  Trump calls these claims a sham and says they're
meant to cripple his president presidential  campaign. If the fraud charges hold up in court,
Trump could lose control of many of his prize  assets and be forced to pay a $250 million fine.
This civil trial is unrelated to four criminal  trials Trump faces in state and federal courts.
"Brian Mann, NPR News, New York."
The federal government did not shut down over  the weekend after Congress passed a short-term
spending bill. The legislation includes billions  of dollars for U.S. emergency disaster help,
but not a cent for aid to Ukraine.  When the bill got to the Senate,
Colorado Democratic Sen. Michael Bennet held it up
for a time until he got a commitment from  leadership to debate funding for Ukraine:
"This is one of those times when we can't  afford to have an institutional failure.
I think this is beyond politics. You know, if  we turn our back on Ukraine, um, we know from
President Zelenskyy that Europe will turn its  back on Ukraine and they will lose the war."
He spoke to NPR's weekend All Things Considered.
Meanwhile, Florida Republican Congressman  Matt Gaetz is seeking to oust House
Speaker Kevin McCarthy. Gaetz says  that McCarthy broke his promises
to hardline House Republicans by working  with Democrats to pass the spending bill.
More than 75,000 Kaiser Permanente health  care workers across the United States are
preparing to go on strike for three days.  The walkout would start this Wednesday.
As NPR's Danielle Kaye reports their  union contract expired over the weekend:
"These Kaiser workers, whose contract expired  on Saturday, include nurses, lab technicians,
pharmacists and many others. They're  represented by a coalition of 12 unions
that's bargaining with Kaiser, one of  the biggest health care providers in
the U.S. The union say Kaiser hasn't offered  adequate solutions to end a staffing crisis,
which they say is negatively affecting patient  care and employees' well-being. Kaiser and the
unions say they're willing to keep bargaining to  reach a deal on a new contract, but if there's
no agreement by Wednesday morning, tens of  thousands of workers will walk off the job.
Kaiser says hospitals and emergency departments  would stay open in the event of a strike.
"Danielle Kaye, NPR News."
Taylor Swift showed up at last  night's NFL game between the
Kansas City Chiefs and the New York  Jets. NPR's Emma Bowman reports that
Swift's star power is giving the NFL a  big opportunity to cash in on her status:
"The pop star returned to MetLife Stadium  in New Jersey, but this time, she wasn't the
headliner — despite all the jokes on NBC's  pregame show, "Football Night in America":
'Ladies and gentlemen, "The Eras Tour"  continues — Taylor Swift is in the building.'
"Swift was there to support  Chief's tight end Travis Kelce,
but the Swifties still showed up. After the  news dropped that the pop star would be there,
the price for last-minute cheap seats rose  by 10% on the ticket marketplace Gametime.
Swift arrived at the stadium with a gaggle of  A-list celebs, but the talk was all Taylor:
'I'm not going to make a Travis Kelce-Taylor
Swift joke. I think we know  those jokes "All Too Well." '
"Swift's last showing at a Chief's game  drove up sales of Kelce's jersey by 400%.
"Emma Bowman, NPR news."
You're listening to NPR.