President Biden will meet in Israel and  Jordan tomorrow with those country's leaders.
And the House may vote today on whether to elect  Ohio Congressman Jim Jordan as its next Speaker.
Good morning. I'm Korva Coleman, from NPR  News, and here are today's top stories:
President Biden leaves this afternoon  for a short trip to Israel and Jordan,
arriving tomorrow. He'll meet in person  with leaders. NPR's Tamara Keith reports
Biden wants to hear about Israel's  military strategy and its needs:
Normally, when a president visits a  war zone, it's done in secrecy — when
Biden went to Ukraine earlier this year, he  took a 10-hour train ride to get to Kyiv,
with virtually no one in the world knowing  about it until he was there. National
Security Council spokesman John Kirby says the  situation is different; Tel Aviv isn't Kyiv:
The security situation is certainly tense, of  course, uh, but we take all those factors into
account when we both plan the president's trip  and when we make a decision to, uh, to preview it.
Polling shows at this moment moment Americans  are very much in favor of showing strong support
for Israel, and that support for an ally at war  is a big part of Biden's agenda with this trip.
Tamara Keith, NPR News.
Meanwhile, Israel continues to strike  at Hamas and Hezbollah targets in both
Gaza and in Lebanon. NPR's Peter  Kenyon reports from Jerusalem:
After an intense 24 hours of continued air  strikes, the Israeli military said it had killed
Osama Mazini, a Hamas official responsible  for those taken prisoner by Hamas and who,
"directed terrorist activities against Israel." To  the north, the IDF announced that it was striking
Hezbollah targets in Lebanon and later said it  had carried out strikes against what it called
terror targets and infrastructure of the Hezbollah  terrorist organization in Lebanon, adding that it
was in response to fire Monday toward Israel. The  IDF Chief of Staff released a message to soldiers
saying, in part, "we took a hard hit and we are  responsible, but now the initiative is in our
hands. The war will be difficult and long," the  message continued, "but the IDF will prevail."
Peter Kenyan, NPR News, Jerusalem.
As Israel continues bombing Gaza, the situation  for Palestinians remains desperate. Palestinian
health officials say the air strikes have left  nearly 2,800 people dead. Israel is blocking all
water, food and fuel from entering the Palestinian  enclave. Relief groups in other countries say the
situation is catastrophic: People in hospitals  cannot get medical aid; there is fear of
disease as people drink dirty water. The U.S. is  pushing Israel to allow relief aid to enter Gaza.
Many people turned out in a Chicago suburb  yesterday to mourn a 6-year-old boy who was
stabbed to death by his landlord,  allegedly. Wadea Al-Fayoume was
Palestinian American. Prosecutors alleged  the landlord targeted him because of his
family's Muslim faith. Mahmoud Yousef  is the boy's great uncle; he says the
fighting between Israel and Hamas militants  should not be reflected here in the U.S.:
You want war? It's overseas. It's not  our war. It's not United States' war,
and we're gathering here to say  we need to save our kids — I'm not
just staying about Palestinians;  I'm staying about our, our kids.
The landlord is charged with murder.
There may be a vote later today in the House  to select a new Speaker. Republicans have the
majority and Ohio Congressman Jim Jordan  won a GOP leadership contest last week,
but he did not have near unanimity of GOP support.
New York Congressman Marc Molinaro  says Jordan has won his backing:
He's assured me that members like me and the  people I represent will have a voice at the table
and uh, uh he's, uh, understands that we need  to govern and, for that, I'll be voting for him.
But it's not clear if Jordan has enough  support: If all members are voting,
Jordan can only afford to lose a few  Republicans in order to win the Speaker's gavel.
This is NPR.