Former President Donald Trump was booked  and released from a Georgia jail last night.
And on Maui, officials have dropped the number  of those listed as missing to around 390.
Good morning. I'm Jeanine Herbst, from NPR  News, and here are today's top stories:
Former President Donald Trump was booked and  released from the Fulton County Jail last
night. In brief remarks departing Atlanta's  Hartsfield-Jackson Airport, he attacked the
charges as a "travesty of justice." Georgia  Public Broadcasting's Stephen Fowler has more:
"Trump faces 13 felony counts under a sweeping  racketeering conspiracy case for trying and
failing to overturn his 2020 election defeat.  After about 20 minutes of processing inside the
jail, including a booking photo, Trump returned  to the Atlanta airport. He defended his actions,
proclaimed his innocence and accused  prosecutors of political meddling:
'What they're doing is election interference —  they're trying to interfere with an election.'
"Eighteen other people also  face charges in the case.
"For NPR News, I'm Stephen Fowler, in Atlanta."
Maui County is suing Hawaiian Electric Company,  claiming the utility was negligent when it
failed to power down electrical equipment during  heavy winds, an oversight the county's leaders
say helped to fuel the deadliest wildfire in  modern U.S. history. Hawaii Electric says it's
disappointed over the suit, as the investigation  into the cause of the fire continues. Meanwhile,
authorities have lowered the number of people  listed as missing from around 1,000 to 388,
and they're releasing their names.  Police Chief John Pelletier:
"Once those names come out, it can and will cause  pain for some folks that are affected by this.
This is not an easy thing to do, but we want to  make sure that we are doing everything we can,
possibly, to make this investigation  the most complete and thorough to date."
The death toll stands at 115 people.
Wall Street will be watching this morning's  speech by Federal Reserve Chair Jerome Powell.
He's scheduled to address economists  and Central Bankers in Jackson Hole,
Wyoming. NPR's Scott Horsley says investors  will be looking for clues on whether the Fed
policymakers might continue raising interest  rates at their next meeting in September:
"Last year, Powell delivered some tough  medicine at Jackson Hole, saying the Fed
would move aggressively to tamp down inflation,  even if that resulted in short-term pain for
families and businesses. Today, there's not  much doubt about the Fed's commitment to getting
prices under control — the central bank has raised  interest rates sharply and inflation has cooled,
from more than 9% last summer to just over 3%  last month. That's still above the Fed's target,
though. Powell and other Fed policy makers  have left the door open to additional rate
hikes. At their last meeting, some members of  the rate-setting committee said it's important
to consider the risk of pushing rates too high  along with the danger of not doing enough.
"Scott Horsley, NPR News, Washington."
You're listening to NPR News, from Washington.