The Justice Department plans  to push for a speedy trial in
former President Donald Trump's January 6th case.
And the Parkland, Florida, school shooting will  be reenacted today as part of a civil lawsuit.
Good morning. I'm Korva Coleman, from NPR  News, and here are today's top stories:
The special counsel prosecuting  former President Donald Trump has
a week to propose a trial date in the  January 6th case. NPR's Carrie Johnson
reports the Justice Department wants  a speedy trial in Washington D.C."
"Prosecutor Thomas Windom says this case, like  any other, should be handled in regular order,
and that means a speedy trial. Former President  Trump pleaded not guilty to four felony charges,
including conspiracy to defraud the U.S. and  conspiracy to obstruct Congress as it certified
ballots on Jan. 6, 2021. Trump's lawyer, John  Lauro, says there's a significant amount of
evidence in the case to review. He suggested Trump  may seek a long-shot bid to move the case to West
Virginia, where more people voted for Trump.  The former president is the front-runner for
the GOP nomination in 2024. He'll be fighting  three criminal cases during the campaign.
"Carrie Johnson, NPR News, Washington."
The National Weather Service says  excessive heat is sticking around
the southwest and south-central parts of  the U.S. Temperatures up to 115 degrees
are expected in Phoenix today. The heat index  will be almost the same today in Oklahoma City.
Heavy thunderstorms are crossing Alabama this  morning. Forecasters have issued flash flood
warnings for some northern parts of the state.  They say as much as four inches of rain have
already fallen and another three inches could  be on the way. Parts of the same area were hit
by storms yesterday. Ten people were hurt  in Etowah County, Alabama, about 60 miles
northeast of Birmingham. Rusty Tidmore ran to  get his daughter off his bus when the storms hit:
"I get to the bus to get my daughter  off the top bunk — trees falling
everywhere — I put a dragger into floor  and I'm holding her in the floor and,
as we hit the floor of the  bus, it lifts off the ground."
More flash flood warnings are also posted this  morning in parts of Missouri and Tennessee.
Today, the shooting that claimed 17 lives  at a high school in Parkland, Florida,
five years ago is being reenacted. NPR's Kristin  Wright reports it's part of a civil lawsuit:
"Ballistics experts will fire live ammunition  from an identical weapon as the gunman from the
same locations inside Marjory Stoneman Douglas  High School. The community has expressed anger,
but the court decided the reenactment might  address a key question. The school resource
officer on duty that day, a sheriff's deputy,  never entered the building. Scott Peterson said
he couldn't hear all of the shots or pinpoint  where they were coming from. University of
Michigan law school Professor Len Niehoff  says reenactments can demonstrate complexity:
'One reason you sometimes admit  demonstrative evidence is to help
the jury understand that they actually know  less about something than they think they do.'
"A judge will decide whether  a recording of the reenactment
is played for the jury. Peterson was  acquitted of criminal charges in June.
"Kristin Wright, NPR News."
This is NPR.