Former President Donald Trump and 18  others have been indicted in Georgia
over alleged efforts to overturn  the results of the 2020 election.
And the search continues for human  remains on the island of Maui.
Good morning. I'm Windsor Johnston, with  NPR News, and here are today's top stories:
Prosecutors in Georgia have indicted  former President Donald Trump. NPR's
Carrie Johnson reports Trump and 18 others  are facing a barrage of criminal charges for
their alleged efforts to overturn the  state's results of the 2020 election:
"Beyond the the overarching charge of a  racketeering, there are a number of other,
more specific charges, including solicitation  of violation of oath by public officer,
false statements and writings, and  impersonating a public officer, forgery,
some document-related charges  and false statements charges."
That's NPR's Carrie Johnson reporting.
Access to west Maui is still being  restricted as authorities continue
to search for human remains in Lahaina after  deadly wildfires. Officials in Hawaii say at
least 99 people have died in the fires.  NPR's Lauren Sommer reports residents on
the island are feeling isolated, lacking  power and cell service in some areas:
"We're hearing from some residents in Lahaina that  they're eager to get back to central Maui — there,
they can get better wifi, supplies and even  search for loved ones. The more direct route
there is being restricted by authorities; they  say that road needs to be left open for utility
trucks and supply chains. If residents  leave, they have to take a much longer,
hourlong road that's very windy and dangerous.  Today, residents in Lahaina got a text message
that they should gather to get special  placards to put in their cars to speed
their return to Lahaina. Many waited hours  to get their placard. The site was quickly
overwhelmed, and authorities shut it down  and said they are abandoning that system.
"Lauren Sommer, NPR News, Lahaina."
Lawyers in Alabama are awaiting a ruling from  federal judges over whether the state's new
congressional map satisfies a Supreme Court  ruling early this year. Stephan Bisaha,
of Gulf States Newsroom, reports the state was  ordered to create two majority black districts,
but the panel of judges raised questions  over the state's new submission:
"Alabama's justification for ignoring the Supreme  Court? A new map and new rules means the court's
order no longer matters. Alabama recently changed  its standards for drawing congressional maps,
so the state's attorneys say its newest map  should be judged against those new standards,
not whether it made two districts where a  minority candidate had a chance at winning.
The three federal judges running the  hearing did not seem impressed — the
same judges who initially found Alabama  violated the Voting Rights Act. One judge
said it seemed like Alabama deliberately  ignored the court's instructions. If the
judges reject the new map, they could appoint  their own officials to draw brand new one.
"For NPR News, I'm Stephan Bisaha, in Birmingham."
This is NPR News.