Two candidates are vying to be  the next Speaker of the House,
and former President Donald  Trump is backing one of them.
And thousands of health care workers  remain on strike against Kaiser Permanente.
Good morning. I'm Korva Coleman, from NPR  News, and here are today's top stories:
It's still unclear who will be the next  Speaker of the House. Former President
Donald Trump initially floated the idea of  temporarily filling the post himself. Now,
he says he's backing Ohio Congressman  Jim Jordan. NPR's Windsor Johnston
reports the other contender for the  speakership is Louisiana's Steve Scalise:
"Congressman Jim Jordan and Steve Scalise  are rushing to lock down the more centrist
members of the conference ahead of a vote that's  expected to take place next Wednesday. Jordan,
the chairman of the powerful House Judiciary  Committee and a fierce defender of Donald Trump,
has pitched himself to his fellow Republicans as  someone who can unify the party, going forward.
Majority Leader Scalise has argued that he has  the experience needed to unite the conference,
having served as part of the House Republican  leadership team for the past 10 years. In order
to become the next speaker, any candidate  will need a simple majority of the House
members who are present and voting.  Historically, that number has been 218.
"Windsor Johnston, NPR News, Washington."
The co-founder of the failed  cryptocurrency exchange FTX has
testified against accused crypto mogul Sam  Bankman-Fried. As NPR's David Gura reports,
Gary Wong testified he committed  fraud at Bankman-Freid's direction:
"The U.S. government alleges Sam Bankman-Freid  defrauded FTX customers and investors and
lenders to the now-defunct cryptocurrency-focused  hedge fund he co-founded called Alameda Research.
On Thursday, jurors heard testimony from a  partner at the venture capital firm Paradigm,
which invested hundreds of millions of dollars  in FTX. Last November, when the cryptocurrency
exchange collapsed, Paradigm marked down  that investment to zero. Prosecutors began
questioning Gary Wong, who started FDX with  Bankman-Freid and pleaded guilty to wire fraud,
securities fraud and commodities fraud charges.  He's a cooperating witness who said in court
he committed those crimes with Bankman-Freid  and others. Wong's testimony continues today.
"David Gura, NPR News, New York."
About 75,000 unionized health care workers  for Kaiser Permanente remain on strike across
the country. They're demanding better wages, and  they're calling on Kaiser to immediately address a
significant staffing shortage in its facilities.  Caroline Lucas directs the coalition of Kaiser
Permanente unions. She says Kaiser patients  also want new health care workers to be hired:
"We are having overwhelming support  from existing Kaiser patients,
who have called, emailed, showed up  to our strike lines to tell us that
they are overwhelmed and tired by the  Kaiser wait to get appointments today."
The strike against Kaiser  will end tomorrow morning.
This year's winner of the Nobel Peace  Prize is Iranian women's rights activist
Narges Mohammadi. She's been honored  for years of activism to ensure human
rights for women in Iran's theocratic  government. Mohammadi is in prison.
This is NPR.