Storms in the U.S. are becoming more costly,
having caused more than $35 billion  in damage already this year.
And it's been 75 years since President  Truman desegregated the military.
Good morning, I'm Korva Coleman, from NPR  News, and here are today's top stories:
More than 180 million people in the U.S. are under  excessive heat warnings or heat advisories. Many
states have soaring temperatures and heat  indexes in the triple digits or close to it,
such as in southern Maine. There are  excessive heat warnings in the southwest,
but also in parts of Kansas, Nebraska,  Missouri, Iowa, Illinois and Minnesota.
Storms in the U.S. have caused at  least $35 billion worth of damage
so far this year. NPR's Rebecca Hersher tells us
that's according to a report from the  German insurance company Munich Re:
"Storms have caused significant damage across  the central and southern U.S. this year. The
costliest single event happened in Texas in  June, when hailstones more than four inches wide
destroyed cars and damaged homes. Losses in  the tens of billions of dollars from such
storms used to be rare, the authors point out,  but are now a regular occurrence. One reason
is that people are moving to places that are  prone to severe thunderstorms and tornadoes.
The storms themselves may also be getting worse  — scientists are still working to understand the
potential connection between severe thunderstorms  and climate change, but climate models suggest
a warmer atmosphere supports powerful  thunderstorms that can spawn tornadoes.
"Rebecca Hersher, NPR News."
The Justice Department is asking a federal  judge to order Texas to remove a floating
barrier in the Rio Grande. Texas Gov.  Greg Abbott ordered the buoys placed to
stop migrants from crossing. Texas  Public Radio's Dan Katz has more:
"The area around Eagle Pass, where  the buoys have been installed,
is a hot spot for border crossings and  an already dangerous part of the Rio
Grande to cross — there have been 89 deaths  and 249 water rescues in the area since 2018,
according to an affidavit from the U.S. Border  Patrol Chief. The Justice Department is asking
for an injunction to require Texas to remove the  buoys within 10 days and to block the state from
installing any more river barriers without prior  approval from the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers.
The buoys are Abbott's latest escalation of his  controversial Operation Lone Star border security
program that's testing the legal limits of a  state's ability to enforce immigration policy.
"I'm Dan Katz ,in San Antonio."
75 years ago this week, President Harry Truman  signed an executive order desegregating the
U.S. military. Defense Secretary Lloyd  Austin, a retired four-star Army general,
is the first Black American to hold the top  Pentagon job. Today, he praised Truman's action:
"That landmark order demanded equality  of treatment and opportunity for all
persons in the armed forces without regard  to race, color, religion or national origin."
Austin is visiting the nation of Papua New  Guinea. The U.S. is trying to strengthen
relationships with Pacific island  nations to counter China's influence.
This is NPR.