Good morning. Today is Monday,  October 16th. I'm Korva Coleman,
from NPR News, and here are today's top stories:
NPR's learned President Biden is delaying  a trip to Colorado that he had planned for
today. Instead, Biden will remain  at the White House to participate
in national security meetings as the conflict  between Israel and Hamas militants continues.
There's still no word on the status of the  border crossing in southern Gaza. Secretary
of State Antony Blinken said yesterday  that it would open to allow humanitarian
relief aid to reach Palestinians and  to let Americans trapped in Gaza get
out into Egypt. White House National  Security Council spokesman John Kirby:
Part of the reason was Hamas was putting up  roadblocks and refusing to let people even
approach the gate, so, again, we're going  to work on this very, very hard — with both
Israel and Egypt. We want to see safe passage  for people that, that, that want to get out.
He spoke to Weekend All Things Considered.  It's not clear that the crossing has yet
opened. Secretary Blinken is back in  Israel today for meetings with leaders.
The head of the World Health Organization  says Gaza is suffering from a "humanitarian
and public health catastrophe." NPR's Ari  Daniel reports this comes amid Israel's
continuing response to Hamas militants,  who attacked more than a week ago:
Hospitals across Gaza are overwhelmed with the  increasing number of patients needing urgent
treatment for injuries caused by Israel's ongoing  bombardment. Dr. Ghassan Abu-Sittah is a plastic
surgeon usually based in London. For the last  week, he's been at Al Awda Hospital in Gaza:
There are patients on mattresses  on the floors everywhere,
and there are over 200 patients who  need to go to the operating room and
and can't because more critically  ill patients are taking precedence.
Abu-Sittah says each day the hospital's tearing  through medical supplies that should last a
month and a half. The WHO says Gaza needs  "the immediate and safe delivery of food,
medical supplies and other humanitarian aid.
ArI Daniel, NPR News.
France is at its highest level of alert  following the fatal stabbing of a teacher
at a high school in the north of the country.  Police say the attack was by a former student
at the school who was described as an Islamist  radical. NPR's Eleanor Beardsley reports:
A 20-year-old Chechen has been arrested in the  school attack, and French Interior Minister
Gérald Darmanin suggested there could be a  link with the violence in the Middle East,
though investigators have yet to announce a  motive. Several Paris tourist destinations
were evacuated briefly Saturday amidst bomb  threats, and 7,000 French soldiers have
been deployed to protect sensitive venues.  Paris' historic Jewish quarter, The Marais,
still seemed bustling, but kosher restaurant  manager Romain Lodé says people are jittery:
Since the war start in Israel, it's  kind of bit different, you know,
it's very quiet. People are scared to  come out. It's very hard, at the moment.
The French government has  banned all pro-Palestinian
demonstrations for fear they could spark violence.
Eleanor Beardsley, NPR News.
Business in the House of Representatives  continues to be frozen because there's no
Speaker. Congressman Jim Jordan won  a GOP leadership election last week
but appears to still be far short  of the votes he needs to win the
speakership election. House Republicans  are expected to meet and talk later today.
You're listening to NPR News.