The UAW is on strike against automakers Ford,
GM and Stellantis after failing to  reach a contract agreement overnight.
And lawmakers in Wisconsin have fired  the state's top elections official.
Good morning. I'm Windsor Johnston, with  NPR News, and here are today's top stories:
About 13,000 U.S. autoworkers are walking  the picket lines this morning just hours
after contract negotiations broke down between the
United Auto Workers union and  Detroit's Big Three carmakers.
Drivers honking their horns in support of striking  workers at the Stellantis plant in Toledo,
Ohio. Stellantis worker Leticia Hummer says  there's no telling how long the strike will last:
"As long as it takes for us to  get a fair, fair contract. I,
I want to look out for my brothers and sisters."
Negotiations broke down between  the United Auto Workers Union
and the three big car makers over  wage increases and other demands.
The death toll from catastrophic  flooding in eastern Libya has surpassed
11,000. That's according to the Associated  Press. Linda Fasulo reports the United Nations
is asking countries for more than $70 million in  assistance to help those impacted by the floods:
"U.N. humanitarian chief Martin Griffiths  says the U.N. is on the ground in Libya,
providing food and medical supplies, and  is deploying what he called a robust team
to support the international response to the  disaster. He described the scale of devastation
as 'shocking' and 'heartbreaking.' Meanwhile, the  director of the U.N. meteorological agency said
most of the casualties could have been avoided  if Libya had an operating weather service that
could have issued warnings and emergency  authorities able to carry out evacuations.
Libya remains in political and military  stalemates, with two competing governments.
"For NPR News, I'm Linda Fasulo, in New York."
Lawmakers in Wisconsin voted to fire the  state's top elections official just months
before the 2024 primary. Anya van Wagtendonk,  from Wisconsin Public Radio, reports the move
sets up an unprecedented legal battle over who's  in charge of elections in the battleground state:
"Republicans, who control the state Senate,  moved to oust Meagan Wolfe. In response,
Wisconsin's Democratic Attorney General, Josh  Kaul, filed suit. Kaul said the Legislature
acted illegally in subjecting Wolfe to  a confirmation vote in the first place.
He's asking a court to confirm that. And  Wolfe said she's continuing in the job:
'There is such important work ahead,
and my hope is that we will quickly get  the clarity that we need from the courts.'
"The procedural wrangling comes after Wolfe  has faced years of criticism from supporters
of former President Donald Trump. They've  accused her of undermining the 2020 election,
which Joe Biden won in Wisconsin  by less than a percentage point.
"For NPR News, I'm Anya van  Wagtendonk, in Madison."
This is NPR News, in Washington.