Hollywood's writers and major studios have reached
a tentative deal that could end  a nearly five-month-long strike.
And thousands of federal wildland firefighters  are bracing for pay cuts later this week.
Good morning. I'm Korva Coleman, from NPR  News, and here are today's top stories:
There's a tentative agreement between  striking writers and Hollywood studios.
If approved by striking writers, it  could end a five-month-long walkout.
Details of the proposed agreement  have not yet been disclosed,
but writer's guild member and strike captain  Bill Wolkoff says he is eager to see the terms:
"I know they would not, uh, have,  uh, told us a tentative deal was
reached — and told us that picketing  is suspended — if it wasn't exemplary."
CEOs from four Hollywood studios  joined negotiators at the table.
They're facing thorny issues — from  higher residual payments when shows
go into reruns and protections  against artificial intelligence.
Thousands of federal wildland firefighters are  bracing for major pay cuts in less than a week
unless Congress intervenes. NPR's Kirk  Siegler reports an expected government
shutdown before then is stoking fears  of mass resignations within the force:
"About 19,000 Federal wildland firefighters could  see their paychecks slashed starting this coming
Sunday unless Congress passes pending legislation  that would give them a permanent increase. Prior
to the fall of 2021, some rookie firefighters  on the frontlines of major wildfires have been
making $15 an hour. That year, U.S. Forest  Service and other federal agency firefighters
got temporary pay raises of up to $20,000 from  the infrastructure law but now those are set
to expire and, in the meantime, efforts to give  wildland firefighters. A permanent pay raise have
stalled in a divided Congress. The union that  represents them as warning of a "mass exodus"
from the workforce just as we're going into the  typical peak of California's wildfire season.
"Kirk Siegler, NPR News, Boise."
President Biden is welcoming several leaders  from Pacific Islands to the White House
today for a summit. The White House says  the forum will focus on climate issues,
economic growth and strengthening security. The  Biden administration is trying to fortify U.S.
relations with Pacific Island nations  to counter China's growing influence.
U.S. border officials have reopened a  railroad bridge in Eagle Pass, Texas.
Texas Public Radio's Jerry Clayton reports, last  week, thousands of migrants crossed into the city:
"The international railway bridge was closed last  Wednesday after a state of emergency declaration
from the city's mayor. Vehicular traffic remains  closed on the international bridge. At one point
last week, around 8,600 migrants crossed  into the U.S. and Eagle Pass in a 24-hour
period. The surge has also overwhelmed migrant  resource centers, such as the one in San Antonio,
which has been averaging around 750 migrants  a day seeking assistance. The U.S. Department
of Defense sent an additional 800 personnel to  the border to handle the increase in crossings
by last Friday. The number of migrants crossing  an Eagle Pass had dropped by around two-thirds.
"I'm Jerry Clayton in San Antonio."
You're listening to NPR News, from Washington.