The White House chief of staff  tells NPR it's on Republicans
to avert a looming government shutdown.
And bans on gender-affirming  care for minors in Tennessee
and Kentucky are being allowed to go into effect.
Good morning. I'm Korva Coleman, from NPR  News, and here are today's top stories:
The White House insists the government  should not shut down this weekend and
that it would not if House Republicans did  their jobs, but as NPR's Asma Khalid reports,
the Biden administration is  working on contingency plans:
"The Office of Management and Budget is  coordinating with federal agencies to ensure
there's a plan in place if the government shuts  down on Sunday. The White House chief of staff,
Jeff Zients, told NPR the president  expects Congress to do the "right thing":
'And if we get into the unfortunate situation  — which we should not — of the government
shutting down, then the president will  communicate with the American people.'
"Zients noted a shutdown would have a big  impact: small business loans and FEMA recovery
efforts would be stalled, active troops and air  traffic controllers would not get paychecks.
"But the main message from this White House  is that there was a deal struck months ago to
fund the government, and House Republicans  need to keep their end of the bargain."
"Asma Khalid, NPR News."
The United Auto Workers could increase  the number of automotive facilities
they're striking today. The union has  said it wants to see more progress in
contract talks with the Big Three U.S. automakers.
Transgender children in Tennessee and  Kentucky will no longer be able to access
gender-affirming care. A federal court has ruled  both states can enforce bans on their care while
respective lawsuits go through the courts. From  member station WPLN, Marianna Bacallao has more:
"The ruling from the Sixth Circuit  is temporary as both states deal with
legal challenges to laws preventing trans kids  from accessing treatment like hormone therapy
and puberty blockers. And a similar ban being  considered in Ohio, also in the Sixth Circuit,
now has a more clear path forward. That  worries plaintiff Samantha Williams,
who had been looking into crossing state  borders to get care for her trans daughter:
'The two states where we were looking to
go for care if the injunction wasn't  granted now have bills of their own.'
"The ruling puts the issue of gender-affirming  care one step closer to the Supreme Court,
as courts have blocked similar banss  in other states from taking effect.
"For NPR News, I'm Marianna  Bacallao, in Nashville."
Officials in New York City say  they've arrested a drug suspect.
They allege he carried about 30 pounds  of fentanyl in a rolling suitcase onto
a city subway. Frank Tarantino is with  the Drug Enforcement Administration:
'It is the most reckless and most  irresponsible thing that traffickers
could do, is move this poison on  the public transportation system."
Officers found more fentanyl in the  suspect's New York City apartment.
This happened just blocks away from another  drug bust last week. A 1-year-old baby died
after being exposed to the drug  in his apartment-based daycare.
You're listening to NPR.