A federal judge has dismissed former  President Donald Trump's defamation
countersuit against writer E. Jean Carroll.
And Zoom is scrapping plans to use  customer data to train its AI tools.
Good morning. I'm Nora Raum, with NPR  News, and here are today's top stories:
President Biden is on a three-state  swing through the western U.S. NPR's
Windsor Johnston reports the president  is starting his trip today in Arizona:
"Biden is expected to announce plans for a new  national monument to preserve one million acres
during a stop today at the Grand Canyon. From  Arizona, Biden will then head to Albuquerque,
New Mexico, to make another pitch for his  economic agenda. On Thursday, Biden will
travel to Salt Lake City, Utah, to mark one year  since Congress passed the bipartisan PACT Act,
which provides benefits to U.S. service  members who were exposed to toxic substances."
NPR's Windsor Johnston.
A federal judge has dismissed former  President Donald Trump's defamation
countersuit against writer E. Jean  Carroll. NPR's Jaclyn Diaz has more:
"Trump and his attorneys had claimed that the  author and former magazine writer defamed Trump
when she said he raped her on CNN. When she said  this, Carroll was being interviewed after she won
one of her lawsuits against Trump. The jury  in that case found Trump liable for sexually
abusing Carroll and defaming her. In dismissing  Trump's countersuit, federal judge Lewis Kaplan
said Carroll's statements repeating the claim  that Trump had raped her were substantially true.
This latest development means  that an upcoming January 15th
trial in a previous lawsuit filed by  Carroll against Trump will continue.
"Jaclyn Diaz, NPR News."
Executives at Zoom say the company  does not use customer data to train
its artificial intelligence tools. As NPR's  Bobby Allen reports, the announcement comes
after reports that Zoom uses what people  say on video calls to advance its AI:
"Tech bloggers recently discovered that  Zoom quietly updated its terms of service
to say that Zoom reserves a right  to train its AI on customers' video,
audio and chat transcripts without explicit  permission. After a backlash from customers,
Zoom went on the defensive, saying in a  statement that it would not use customer
data to improve its AI without consent. But  critics point out that Zoom has a poor track
record on data privacy. Zoom was criticized  in 2020 after providing end-to-end encryption
only to customers who paid for the service. A  year later, the company agreed to a $85 million
settlement over sharing customer data with  Google, Facebook and LinkedIn without consent.
"Bobby Allen, NPR News."
The polls are open in Ohio in a special election.
Voters are deciding whether to raise the  threshold for amending the State Constitution
and to impose more stringent standards to  get an amendment on the ballot in the first
place. Abortion rights activists oppose the  changes. In November, voters in Ohio are to
consider a proposed constitutional amendment  to protect access to abortion in the state.
You're listening to NPR News, from Washington.